I'll put my cross-section in.
Okay.
Otherwise, I'll keep looking at my cross-section.
I won't go to the full screen for the pvp.
I'll just do it in the operating room.
Okay.
The full screen will take up two screens.
It won't be very convenient to operate.
Okay.
Hello, everyone.
This is my first live stream, so I'm a little nervous.
If I turn the car over, I'll be in trouble.
Okay, okay.
Let's have the teacher introduce himself first.
Introduce myself?
The title of today's video is too high.
Actually, the content is not that high.
That kind of content is more down-to-earth, you see.
Let me introduce myself personally.
The name is here.
Yang Fong Cheng.
It's a real name, a real name.
I mainly play on the A station.
I usually play on the A station.
I don't really pay much attention to the B station.
This time, I'm going to do a live broadcast.
Thank you very much, MZ official.
Thank you very much.
The teacher is too kind.
Thank you for taking care of me on the first time I came to the B station.
And then the main thing is to welcome the A station.
And now I'm working at an animation company.
And then my job is to make the role model.
So, because MZ actually shows us the role model.
That's it.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
I can't talk about it.
So for the character personnel, MZ must be in control.
In the past, it seems that there was no such thing as a character before Lawrence appeared.
The role model should be very high.
At that time, all the so-called role models were all hand-drawn.
That requires a lot of time to practice.
It's just that the level of the role is very good.
Can I put this A station over here?
Yes, you can.
Okay.
This is my A station.
Are we officially starting now?
Or do you want to wait a little longer?
We can talk about what the teacher will talk about today.
Because it seems that there are some friends who are asking,
what do you want to talk about today?
Thank you for your attention.
Okay.
For today, I'll talk about what I talked about in the first half.
In the second half, I'll talk about what I wrote.
In the first half, I'll talk about three parts.
The first part is actually a bit more complicated.
It's more theoretical.
Because I personally think that it's better to start from the beginning.
Before you do something, you need to understand it thoroughly.
You need to think about it thoroughly.
After that, you can make a decision.
It won't take too much time.
There is a word called experience.
There is also a word called pre-experience.
These two words are all words in philosophy.
Pre-experience means some prediction.
Before we do something,
we need to have some rules and regulations in advance.
We can predict the effect we want.
Then we can make a decision.
If we do this,
it will save us a lot of time and a lot of time.
So in my daily work and studies,
I often summarize some theories.
In the past,
I may have written some very strange theories.
I may have seen some very strange things.
These are some of the summary of my work.
In my case,
in the first half,
there may be a little more time.
It's theoretical.
It may take 20-30 minutes.
It's not a theoretical talk.
In the middle,
there may be some practical tips.
In the process of using MD,
I have summarized some tips on software operation.
This may be half theory and half operation.
I will open the software and talk about it in the software.
Because there are a lot of parameters in MD.
There are a lot of parameters.
Most of you are very familiar with it.
Many of my colleagues have done some kind of translation.
They even have a picture translation.
Because in the past,
I have been in contact with MD for a long time.
Not too long.
Because my career is not very long.
My actual working time is only five years.
I have been in the industry for six years.
I have been in the industry for five years.
In the middle,
I have been in the industry for a year.
Okay.
Yes.
So in the beginning,
when I first started in the industry,
I started to get in touch with MD.
At that time,
I was the one who made the decision at the beginning.
Although I made some changes in the middle,
I have been in contact with MD for a long time.
It has been five or six years since then.
At that time,
I remember it was the fourth edition of MD4.
There was no Chinese at that time.
That was a long time ago.
Yes, a long time ago.
But actually,
there were many people earlier.
At that time,
I was not the first one.
I was the fourth one.
At that time,
there was no Chinese.
There was no translation.
There were no attributes.
It was very difficult to use.
But I am very grateful to our project.
The boss of our company,
he made one by himself.
Actually,
I learned a lot from him.
He made one by himself.
It is a translation with various attributes.
It is a translation of the main film
plus the text.
He made a text for us.
Every time I needed to do something,
when I needed to do the costume,
I would open the text.
I would read it on the left side
and operate it on the other side.
How to understand this attribute?
What is the effect of this attribute?
But in this way,
at the beginning,
as a newcomer,
as an intern,
the company may be more tolerant to us.
We will have a lot of time
to try to make mistakes.
But if you are a middleman,
you are at the top of the company,
or a middleman,
or even when you need to guide others,
time is precious.
You can't...
I need to adjust something.
I need to find my document first.
Find my manual.
Find my manual and see
what is the effect of this attribute.
Then I will do another operation.
This may take a lot of time.
In addition, this attribute is really too...
I think it is too...
I just made it up.
You can take a look.
It is a bit difficult to understand this attribute.
Yes.
Especially when there was no Chinese before.
This attribute is too much.
It's getting bigger and bigger.
Last time I saw you,
Beta seemed to be saying
that you were also saying
that you might consider
optimizing this attribute.
Yes.
We have this plan now.
That is to say,
because if we just
go directly to the current name
and usage,
many users
who are not in the clothing industry,
they might not be able to understand it.
Yes, they might not be able to understand it.
Yes, these translations
are a bit too abstract.
We are also considering
whether we should change it
to a more intuitive data to adjust it.
Yes.
So I have a part today.
Actually, in my usual work,
I have already told some of my colleagues,
my classmates.
I have also summarized
a very simple way
of optimizing an attribute.
We will talk about it later.
Actually, there is not much to talk about.
It's just a very simple theory.
We will talk about it later.
This is in our program.
Today's plan is to explain it one by one.
When I first started using AMD,
my computer was i3,
i3, i2, i3, i3.
How many?
Yes.
The performance was very poor.
If I had to make clothes,
it would be very painful.
So I have developed
some good working habits.
I have to achieve the effect
I want with limited performance.
But now everyone's computers
are just playing around.
They are 8 cores and 16 cores.
They are just playing around.
In addition,
AMD has released GPU calculations.
It will be much faster.
But I don't support GPU.
I don't support GPU.
My company in Hong Kong supports it.
I have tried it.
GPU is very fast.
Very fast.
But I think it's too fast.
Yes.
Sometimes,
when you haven't reacted to it,
the effect is gone.
Sometimes,
we want a middle value effect.
It's not the most important effect.
Yes.
So I think
the CPU is slow.
It's similar to
the delay of a video.
What do you mean by that?
A video takes a long time.
Oh, the delay of a video.
Yes.
If you take a video
that's hundreds of times longer,
you can take a video
that takes the same amount of time
for a longer period of time.
Then it will be more convenient
for us to work in detail.
Because the GPU
will be gone in a second.
It will be gone in a second.
Very fast.
Yes.
And the GPU,
I found that
for each layer,
if you have two or three layers,
the knowledge is very poor.
Even if it's one layer,
there will be a difference with the base.
Yes.
I remember
at the beginning of FND4,
even if you use CPU,
there will be a difference.
That's because
it's a version
of the previous version of FND4.
Because each of our versions
will focus on those functions.
They will optimize
the stability of the simulation.
Including the stability of the GPU simulation
is also in the process of optimization.
But because
the development of GPU simulation
optimization is a very, very
difficult thing.
So we have to spend a lot of energy
on this optimization.
So it may take a little longer.
But I think
I can already
meet the current resolution speed.
Many users think that
the CPU simulation
resolution speed
actually takes a long time.
But for me,
I am also more inclined to use CPU.
Because CPU simulation,
as you said,
it will be a bit like
a slowdown.
And in the middle,
I will also have this kind of operation.
I really like it.
That's why I have the time to react.
Yes, I really like to
simulate the dual-channel control.
And then just let it stop,
stop, stop, stop.
Yes, me too.
Yes.
And then when I like
that form,
I may keep it there
with that form.
Yes.
Why is it so slow?
One of the most common problems
when working with many hard Arnak tools
is pretty slow.
It's like
drawing the ZB model.
From the very beginning,
I ususally draw a ZB model
based on the highest armor bricates.
I don't know how and why
the model is descriptions of me.
That's the reason.
What we need to do
in the beginning is to progress.
We firstigen the Martin Luther's obrigon
modeling for the very beginning
and then we scaling down
Some more detailed ones are smaller and easier to control.
It may look slow, but the accuracy is much higher.
Yes.
What did you say?
You said that when you use MG4, it will make a difference.
It will also make a difference in the base.
If the base is too low, the peak is too small.
I think it is because of the peak.
Yes, we always use the peak.
A lot of people have the same problem.
For example, it is easy for the fingers to get in contact with the wood.
It is because there is a lot of space between the fingers.
The fabric space between the fingers is 20 mm.
It is actually quite big.
So it is easy to encounter this problem.
The space between the fingers is small.
It can effectively avoid some of these problems.
Because the number of networks has changed a lot.
Yes, GPU simulation is relatively easy to penetrate.
I saw a small friend asking in the chat.
Because GPU simulation has some different performance from CPU.
Their acceleration performance will cause GPU simulation itself to have some problems when processing layers.
So in the process of processing, it may need to increase the conflict thickness a little bit.
Yes.
In order to prevent some of these problems.
Yes, but there are some things that may not be understood about the conflict thickness.
I will just say that there is a very important reason for the conflict thickness.
It will affect the effect of the fold.
In the production of actual projects,
it is necessary to pay attention to the quality control.
Yes.
There is no need to pay attention to the quality control of the control problem.
In the past, GPU's performance was not very good,
but now without a lot of problems.
Now it is better.
I think there is basically no problem.
It has passed several tens of minutes.
It is OK.
I will introduce my model right away.
Then we will talk about the second step.
The third step is the current MDG and ZD processes.
Many of my students may already know or have their own way of dealing with it.
But it's still the same.
These processes still have their own advantages and disadvantages.
Although I will encounter this problem,
I still don't have the best solution.
I think this problem...
Today, I will introduce two methods.
Actually, I will introduce three methods.
In the future, I will introduce Emily Tofu's method.
When Emily talked about Tofu, I was very happy.
I felt that Tofu was saved.
Tofu was finally saved.
I have been looking for many years of Tofu methods,
but none of them is perfect.
Emily's Tofu method
is not as good as I expected.
But for now,
it's still not very good.
It's not very good.
Tofu is also one of the main ways we want to optimize.
For now,
if we want to develop a new version of our software,
the first thing to consider is the simulation speed,
and Tofu.
Because a lot of friends will think that
we have received a lot of requests
asking if we can get ZD Rematch to MDG.
ZD Rematch?
I'll just...
I'll just mention it.
In the beginning, I might write
Tofu.
When it comes to developing a new feature,
I might write
Tofu development needs.
Later, I'll just write ZD Rematch.
I think ZD Rematch is still too unintelligent.
We still need Tofu.
ZD Rematch is because
there is a very famous problem.
You can't guarantee...
If I have one piece of clothing,
two pieces of clothing,
and two pieces of clothing,
the ZD Rematch will be completely the same.
I can't guarantee that.
So ZD Rematch should have a fatal flaw.
Okay, let's get started.
We have 20 minutes left.
Okay.
As I said earlier,
I'm only going to talk about the theoretical stages.
There might only be pictures or videos.
If you don't like it,
if you like theoretical things,
you have to bear with it.
But I think theory is very important.
Why?
I've seen other excellent teachers
who have done a lot of theoretical memorization.
And there are a lot of people who
are very good at looking at works.
But you don't know
how they work behind the scenes,
how they prepare for work,
how they do a lot of research,
or what they do.
We only see the ice on the sea.
We don't see the ice below the sea.
So I think theory is more important
than the ice below the sea.
In conclusion,
it is also a kind of training for our thinking.
Okay, let's get started.
I'll use my PS.
In the beginning,
I might say
there are a lot of theories
that I've heard before.
But my theory
is mainly about
the role models
that can be used
in the CG industry.
I'm not talking about
the theories that can be used
in every life.
I'm talking about
specific use scenarios
in the game industry
or in the entertainment industry.
In terms of theory,
there are a lot of theories.
I'll use a picture
later
to show you
a specific example.
I'll use a picture
later
to show you
a specific example.
I'll use a picture
later
to show you
a specific example.
Before looking at the picture,
I would like to
take a look at
the location
of the different
nodes.
I need to
take a screenshot.
I need to take a screenshot.
The nodes are closely related
to the body of the character.
They are in the
mutual representation.
Nodes are
the external line of the body.
Nodes are the external line of the body.
The body's reaction to
force is a bit complicated.
First,
the nodes appear
in the joints.
For example, the shoulder,
the elbow,
the wrist,
or the waist.
They are all movable.
Like this one.
This one.
The main nodes
appear in these places.
They are very obvious.
There are also nodes
that move forward and backward.
Okay.
For example,
the first one is a shoulders.
The shoulders are mainly
in the gluteal section.
The gluteal section
is where the arms
and the joints rotate.
The shoulders are the axis.
They rotate.
This force
is like the force
of an inner body.
So the shoulders
are the shoulders.
The shoulders are the shoulders.
We also have cramps in the hip area.
The cramps in this area are caused by the movement of our legs.
The legs will lift up, and the angle of the legs will keep changing.
This is where the cramps occur.
The cramps in the hip area are also caused by the movement of the legs.
When the legs are lifted up, the cramps are in the front.
When the legs are straight, the cramps are in the back.
This is where the cramps occur.
I will talk about a concept later.
The cramps we make in a practical project
are not static.
They are not static.
They are in a state of pure physics.
What we need to make is a semi-movement cramp.
Some cramps need to be understood in a more legal way.
I think this is very important.
We need to consider that the cramps are suitable for all types of movements.
This is very important.
If it's in a game,
if it's in a movie,
or if it's in a real-time analysis,
then of course it's not.
But if it's in a game,
our cramps are basically dead cramps.
They are fixed cramps.
You have to recover the movement of your joints.
So what we need to do is not only to consider a static effect,
but also to consider a dynamic effect.
Yes, because we have a lot of clients.
There are a lot of game clients.
They will say,
they want to achieve a good cramp under static.
When I first came into contact with such a demand,
I was very confused.
I understood later.
Because in the game,
you can't say that these cramps are calculated in such a large amount.
Yes, the calculation is very huge.
Yes, because the calculation is really too huge.
So they may need something under static.
For example, A-pose or T-pose.
It's very dynamic,
or it makes people feel the cramps.
Yes.
In most cases,
it's a suitable cramp.
This is really very important.
Okay.
Let me talk about the second type,
which is the pull type.
The pull type occurs between two joints.
For example,
the shoulder.
We often see the cramps grow like this.
Or backwards.
If the shoulder is a sleeve,
the shoulder will go this way.
Because of this point here,
or this point here,
the two joints may have different directions of movement.
Because of the fabric,
it is less flexible.
Generally speaking,
the fabric is more flexible.
Therefore,
it is more flexible.
Generally speaking,
the fabric is more flexible.
Therefore,
it will reflect its shape.
It will become a linear pull type.
It will be a growth direction like this.
Because here,
the cramp can rotate backwards.
When it rotates,
the distance between these two joints
may increase.
Because it rotates in a arc.
Once it increases,
the pleats are not enough.
When the fabric is not enough,
the shape changes.
The shape changes.
The fabric is pulled forward.
Especially when it comes to sports, it is very obvious.
I saw a video of a player playing a game in the U.S.
I felt that he was doing both kinds of push-ups,
one was behind his buttocks.
When he lifted his leg, there was no push-up.
He probably used two sets of push-ups.
I found that the buttocks were the only place
where I could avoid the push-ups.
Because the buttocks were the only place
I found that the buttocks were the only place
where I could avoid the push-ups.
It was difficult for him to lift his leg.
When he lifted his leg, there was no push-up.
It was difficult to do a combination.
He could only do a set of push-ups.
This is not a combination.
It is a combination of the two.
It's not a combination.
But no push-ups.
It depends.
He's got to do push-ups.
He has to do push-ups.
If you can go into a combination with him,
you will be able to do more push-ups.
He can easily do push-ups.
If you can go into a combination with him,
he can easily do push-ups.
He can easily do push-ups.
It's not a big deal.
It's just a ray of light.
So, if he wants to put the quality on every link,
the requirement is very high.
The third one is the top-down type.
The top-down type is easy to understand.
For example, the male type is not very obvious.
Let me find one that is more obvious.
For example, this one is very obvious.
But this one is relatively rare.
It is the part of the joints or the protruding part of the body
that will push the material out.
This one is very obvious.
It is a ray of light.
For example,
this is a ray of light.
This is the type of ray of light that is pulled out of the body.
At the bottom,
because of the stack below,
the stack is pulled out.
When pulled out,
When it's stuck in the pants,
it may cause some kind of tree-like
or tied-up ray of light.
The top-down type is the top-down type.
I think the most important two joints are the knee and the index finger.
These two joints and the shoulder are basically a single-directional movement.
The shoulder is a little bit special.
The index finger only moves forward.
The index finger moves straight forward.
The index finger can't move backward.
So the index finger can only move in this direction.
If your index finger looks like this,
if your index finger looks green like this,
then your index finger is wrong.
It's not wrong.
It may look like this in a static state.
But in a real project,
it may not be in line with its movement.
If it is in line with its movement,
it may have an impact.
It may not be in line with the movement.
So these two joints are fixed patterns.
For example, the shoulder.
The shoulder is definitely like this.
It doesn't have the highest point.
It only moves in two directions.
It moves in four directions.
So the shoulder moves like this.
Generally speaking,
the shoulder moves like this.
The back moves like this.
It moves like this.
But in reality,
if your index finger is too tight,
it may have problems with your board.
Or if your index finger is in other directions,
It may have problems with your body.
That's why we need to learn the
Because we all learn about modeling.
We learn about modeling.
In fact,
we have almost zero knowledge of
fashion design.
I have read some documents,
but after all,
we must understand the context.
Some problems are really...
Either you know the principles,
or you have experience.
You have been to many places.
You'll know what to do.
But if you have lived in the past,
If you are a professional,
you will know where the problem is in a blink of an eye.
The principle of the knee is the same as the elbow.
The knee only bends backward.
So the elbow can only be like this.
The knee is the highest point, and the elbow bends forward.
But in the actual calculation process,
in many cases, this is not the case.
This is a point that can easily be overlooked.
Let me find another picture.
In real life, many elbows don't bend forward like this.
They are probably horizontal.
For example,
let me find an example.
This one is fine.
This leg here is all horizontal.
Because the leg is too straight,
it doesn't have the highest point.
So it becomes an horizontal elbow.
This kind of elbow should be avoided in the calculation process.
I will talk about this later.
I will put it down first.
I have already talked about the upper part.
Next, I will talk about the drop type.
The drop type is easy to understand.
It is the elbow with gravity and gravity.
It is an image of gravity on the earth.
For example, this person is wearing a skirt.
Let me put on a skirt for him.
This skirt is very loose.
His elbow will only be like this.
It will only be like this.
It is impossible for it to grow like this.
Yes.
So the drop type is easy to understand.
There are many types of this type in the actual project.
For example, this person is wearing a skirt or a scarf.
This type of situation is easy to see.
Of course, I am talking about the general situation.
In general situations, if the fabric is a little softer,
it will be like this.
There will also be some types of this type.
There will also be some strange situations.
For example, when an artist puts on a skirt.
If the skirt is big like this,
the fabric will fold like this.
The fabric will fold like this,
like this, or like this, or like this.
Check the shape.
Let me turn it over again.
This is the lid.
This material is very hard.
It may not appear on the tree.
If it appears on the tree,
it may appear too cold and cold on the human body.
It may appear on the tree like this.
This is the type of chrysanthemum.
It's a bit of a fixed dead chrysanthemum.
It may also appear on the tree.
I'll tell you a simple principle.
The harder the material,
the more it is inclined,
the softer it is, the more it is inclined,
the more it is soft,
the more it is affected by gravity.
Yes.
If you want to have a soft chrysanthemum,
you need a narrow chrysanthemum inside.
It may be a little square.
It may be a little bit like this,
like this.
The soft chrysanthemum
will become a little more horizontal
when it is tied up like this.
The loose part above
may become a little more like this.
The next one is a amygdala.
The amygdala is actually
It's easy to understand.
For example, the picture we just saw,
the line on the knee is this kind of line.
It's the clavicle.
The clavicle is here.
But we can't see the clavicle on the knee.
The clavicle is a part of the body.
It may be the joint,
but it has a very small range of motion.
For example, the back of the head.
Or the ankle.
The clavicle is here,
but it doesn't move too much.
That's why it often appears here.
It's like this.
Clavicle-shaped clavicles are basically X-shaped.
They are horizontal.
Like this.
But in the actual process,
it may come down diagonally,
then turn around,
like this.
It's not like the clavicle on the top
is horizontal.
It can't get into the throat.
Next, we have a fixed dead body.
This is easy to understand.
For example, we put some cloths
on the floor at night.
Then we put some heavy objects on it.
The next day,
the whole body is broken.
Then we find a very obvious picture.
There is no need to master this theory.
Just pay attention.
Some types of cloths
may have a fixed body,
but some types don't.
For example,
a fixed body
is like a hard cloth.
It's like a kind of clay.
It may not have a fixed body.
When a fixed body appears,
it may be a little thin and hard.
It may have a weak elasticity.
For example,
this kind of cloth
is a fixed dead body.
Fixed dead bodies are not very useful.
Because sometimes,
we don't know how it should grow in an area.
We don't know what direction it should grow in.
Then we make a pile of dead bodies.
It may look like this,
but we don't know where it is.
Then we can make a fake one.
There is another very important point.
It can improve our truthfulness.
There are many types of cloths in our lives.
If we scan them,
we can see that the dead bodies are very deep.
Like this one.
We can see that the dead bodies are very deep.
If we make a fake one,
we don't dare to make it so deep.
But if you make a new one,
and it is completely empty,
and you make a patch,
and make a back,
and make a patch,
then your cloths will become more and more smooth.
Then you can make a new one.
In this case,
we can make a fake one.
Let me see what the next one is.
I have already said that
the purpose of making a fake one
is to satisfy the soul in the greatest degree.
I have already said that.
Let me repeat it.
There are some types of cloths
that we should try to avoid.
For example, the anti-movement direction.
I have already given an example.
I will give more examples later.
There are also some non-physical ones,
which are not controlled by the joints and muscles.
We should try to avoid them.
There is also the lack of clarity of movement.
The sense of fastness is obvious.
If the movement is not clear,
then sometimes,
it is a very painful problem.
This place needs a cloth,
but we can't arrange a suitable one for it.
Because sometimes,
if you arrange a cloth,
other cloths will be repeated,
or there will be conflicts.
Especially if it is repeated.
There is also a sense of unity,
which is very obvious.
I will find some pictures later
to explain it to you in detail.
There are also non-physical ones,
which are not controlled by the joints and muscles.
Those are non-physical,
like heavy and thin-eradобрated equipment.
Theistes Alternatively,
cuirass joints are hard to reach.
For example,
there are some false joints there.
a foreign although you ride a car in the field,
there can have a real problem in the correct form.
They could be complicated,
and not smooth.
There is no sense of unity there.
I have already made an effort in the direction of the reaction.
For example, this point here must be going forward.
The big bone starts to rotate forward.
This is how it rotates inward.
Because this big bone rotates inward.
If your point is going like this,
it may not be right, it may not be suitable.
For example, when we first started to learn painting,
the math teacher would ask us some questions.
He would say, the point here is like this.
You may be surprised. It's like this.
If your point is like this,
it's not wrong.
It's just that,
it may be a little strange when it actually moves.
Or it may appear that the paint is not very natural.
It is a plate with a special condition.
In this case,
we should try to avoid it as much as possible
in a real CG project.
The sense of unity is relatively obvious.
We need to find some specific pictures to show you.
Because there are many kinds of characters.
The purpose of art is to select.
I think the purpose of art is to select
some beautiful ones and avoid the ugly ones.
The sense of unity is particularly obvious.
For example, this picture in the middle.
This one in the middle.
The direction of the movement is very blurred.
It is completely covered with a bag.
The background.
In a real project,
we need to consider the state of movement.
For example, this place.
If this person moves backwards,
this part becomes an unpressurable state.
This is an unpressurable state.
They don't know how to compress it.
It will transform.
If you are an X-shaped person,
If you compress it up and down,
it will be formed.
Its logic will not change.
If you use a lid, it will be covered.
Yes.
In fact there is a very simple concept
there is a very simple concept
There is a dynamic space
for the region together with the logistic region.
For this,
Yes, this example is very obvious, a triangle and a quadrilateral.
For example, if the shape of this triangle is a quadrilateral,
what we actually need is a quadrilateral.
It is active, it is in an unstable state.
It is in a state that can be modified at any time.
There are two quadrilaterals squeezed together.
I need to find a picture to show you this.
This is very common in real life.
It is very dangerous, the picture you just showed me.
Yes, it is very dangerous.
Lower it a little bit.
This picture is very good, but it also has some other problems.
For example, these are two opposite quadrilaterals.
They are not quadrilateral quadrilaterals, but quadrilateral.
They are squeezed too close together.
If they are squeezed too close together,
they will become like this.
This is very dangerous for a quadrilateral.
For example, I will draw two cross-sectional quadrilaterals.
If they are quadrilaterals,
I will draw a dot here, a dot here, and a dot here.
Three sections are enough.
But if they are like this,
I will draw a dot here, a dot here, a dot here, and a dot here.
So many.
If you only use three dots,
because if we are playing a game,
we need to think of a single,
easier expression,
the dot here, and this one,
you can make it look like a rainbow or like a black and white.
From the top the colour will be too obvious.
It will look very doğru and tiny,
if the light is not good enough,
it will look very strange.
You can see the difference.
This is an example.
related to the next part of the session.
It's already past 5, that's great.
In the next part, I will talk about some
small tips in the actual use process.
I will do some practical demonstrations in the software.
For example, some ways to save energy.
We have already talked about it.
And then there is the difference between
the actual cost of the project and the cost of the exhibition.
And if we can't fully present the cost on a piece of clothing at a time,
I may have calculated the cost with my hands,
but my legs,
for example, may not look very good.
If my legs and my waist are ready,
for example, a piece of clothing that is glued together,
and if I get the other parts ready,
the pleats that I was satisfied with may be broken again.
Is it possible to freeze the area now?
Yes, it is possible.
There are some steps to freeze the area now,
but the performance requirement of the computer is relatively high.
Yes, and it may not be particularly perfect
for the fusion part.
Yes, it may not be particularly perfect for the fusion part.
I will open a file.
For example, we have some...
I just said it at the beginning.
It's a very simple one.
For example, we have a lot of parameters for this material.
If we don't have a translator,
I won't be able to see it.
I won't be able to see a lot of things.
If I don't have a translator, what should I do?
How can I quickly and simply understand
what these parameters are for?
After a few years, I realized that this is not a problem.
I think the most important thing we need to pay attention to
is these five parameters.
A very simple principle is that the larger the number,
the smaller the focus.
These four parameters.
If the number is larger, the harder the material.
One is a golden line, the other is a silver line.
Usually, the material is a flat surface.
If you want to make it finer,
you might make it different.
If you don't pay attention to it,
or you want to simply understand it,
you can make it a flat surface.
We are making these two characters the same,
and we are keeping them the same.
The bigger the number, the harder the fabric will be.
The smaller the number, the softer the fabric will be.
If you want to make oilcloth or leather armor,
you need to make the number as high as 50 or more.
If you want to make sand or silk,
something very thin and soft,
you only need to make the number smaller.
For example, my number is 10, 20, 30, and so on.
Maybe 50 is a dividing line.
If you want to make the number in the middle,
you need to make it in the direction of X.
If the number in the X-shape is bigger,
then the fabric will be smaller.
The more the number of folds you make,
the more your fabric will be affected.
It is divided into diagonal folds
and even four-dimensional folds.
You can see them here.
I have raised the number a little bit.
The fold is going to be a little bit cuckoo's.
If the number is eight,
then it is equal to twenty-five.
If the x-axis is smaller, it will fall down easily and become a very relaxed state with a lot of gravity.
The gravity will affect it a lot.
It will slowly fall down.
I think it is lagging a bit.
There is a problem with the translation of the angle line.
It is actually the third type of the golden tail sand intensity.
There is also a sixth type of the curve intensity.
The sixth in your physical attributes is also called the curve intensity.
It is also the curve intensity of the oblique.
In real life, there is a line in the shape of the clothes you are wearing.
There are a lot of lines.
There are also a lot of lines in the shape of the horizontal line.
The density of their arrangement is different.
For example, if you have two horizontal lines in the same square centimeter,
it is two horizontal lines and two vertical lines.
It is four horizontal lines and four vertical lines.
It must be different.
The angle line is similar to the total number of roots they form in the direction of the angle line.
You can understand it like this.
Therefore, when the angle line is larger,
it will produce irregular wrinkles in the diagonal or 45-degree angle.
Its principle is actually a bit similar to the golden tail sand intensity.
But you can imagine that you suddenly add a lot of roots.
Let its density become larger.
Arrange more closely.
It will produce such wrinkles.
Then there are two other important parameters.
The density and the friction coefficient.
The more the density is larger,
the more it will fall down.
The more the density will fall down.
It really changes the shape of the fabric.
Because sometimes,
our fabric properties have already been adjusted.
There may be some parts that I have already fixed and wanted.
But I want it to be a little more loose.
I want it to have more of a downward feeling.
Then I will adjust it.
I find that it will also affect the number of wrinkles.
The smaller it is, the less it will produce wrinkles.
But in this kind of skirt,
the clothes will look more obvious.
Clothes with tighter pants will not look as obvious.
Yes.
Because the density is like this.
In fact, in the process of making clothes,
a piece of clothing will have its own gravity.
It is gravity.
So it will cause it to have a number of wrinkles.
Because the earth is full of gravity,
so it will have a number of wrinkles.
In addition to this,
it is because our clothes are not one line at a time.
It is one line at a time.
When its elastic strength is greater than its own gravity,
then this dress is actually resisting the gravity of the earth.
Then it will have wrinkles.
So when the elastic strength is relatively high,
the weight of this dress no longer affects the main factor of the wrinkle form.
It becomes its own pull to produce wrinkles.
So the strength of the scarf,
as well as the strength of the toe line,
the bigger it is,
the more wrinkles it will have on our visual effects.
The more wrinkles it will have.
Yes.
Then why is the density here a bit similar?
When your density becomes larger,
the whole pants will be pulled down.
But for a relatively soft fabric,
its weight itself is greater than its own weight.
Yes.
Its weight is greater than its own strength.
So when you increase the density,
when you decrease the density,
it will not be able to withstand the weight.
It is like finding a stronger one among the two forces.
Use a bigger force.
Yes.
As a result, its weight is also very small.
Its own pull is also very small.
So when you increase the density,
the whole pants will no longer have wrinkles.
Because there is no external force affecting it.
This is why when a fabric is relatively soft,
when you increase the density to zero,
it will not have as many wrinkles.
It is because it has no strength.
Yes.
Okay.
The next one I think is very important.
It is friction.
Yes.
It is very important.
These are very important.
I want to move this on the sleeves.
Let me move these.
If the friction is too small,
the fabric will slip down directly.
The fabric will slip down directly.
There will be no wrinkles in the middle.
It will go over directly.
It will not be able to hang the fabric on its body.
If we want to make a little bit rough,
a little bit hard fabric,
we can make the Mothanli bigger.
Yes.
After the Mothanli is bigger,
it will have a very obvious feeling.
It will be stuck on the body.
Yes.
If we want to make a little bit rough,
we can make the Mothanli bigger.
Otherwise, it will go over directly.
Yes.
If we want to make a little bit rough,
a little bit hard,
it will not be able to hang the fabric on its body.
Yes.
If we want to make a little bit rough,
we can make the Mothanli bigger.
Of course, it depends on the material.
If we want to make a little bit hard,
we can make the Mothanli bigger.
If we want to make a little bit soft,
it will be impossible.
So, if we make a little bit more,
it will rest on the fabric.
Yes.
The Mothanli is not like a mass between cloths,
or a mass between the body and the fabric.
Yes.
Because, the friction,
in fact, this version seems to be a little complicated,
it's originally called the friction coefficient.
The friction coefficient, actually, is just a fabric. It is because, in our real life, every object has its own friction coefficient.
The greater the friction coefficient, the more difficult it is for us to make our fabric rust.
It's more like sandpaper, it's rough on the surface, and when it's very rough, the friction of the object will be greater, and it will stay in that place.
It is more likely to be affected by the body.
Yes, it is more likely to be affected by the body. So when we make some pants, we usually avoid the wrinkles that need to be piled up.
Some people may want to keep the wrinkles like this, so they may want to increase the amount of friction.
If they don't want to have wrinkles like this, they will have to reduce it.
Because it's easy to pile up wrinkles here on the knee.
You can imagine why there are some wrinkles piled up in this place when wearing pants in real life.
It's because your thighs are tight.
Because there is a prominent muscle in the thigh muscle.
The gluteus medius muscle.
Yes, the gluteus medius muscle is easy to make the pants, because the pants are slowly shrinking.
The pants are slowly shrinking.
It's not based on the muscle.
Yes, so when it's in the muscle, it will be stopped here.
Yes, it will be stopped here.
Yes, so when you have a lot of friction, it will get tighter and tighter.
So there are a lot of wrinkles that will stop here.
At this time, you may come back and reduce the amount of friction.
There may not be so many wrinkles.
And the amount of friction will be useful when making clothes like this.
They are doing some, for example, knotting.
Some people may want to tie a tie.
Or some people want to tie a butterfly knot.
When you tie a knot, the fabric is slippery.
The fabric is very slippery in normal situations.
When you tie a knot, in real life, your hands may be holding the belt.
It has a force.
There is an external interference.
Yes, there is an external interference.
But when you tie a knot in MD, there is no external interference.
The fabric itself is relatively easy to slide.
It's not like the strength between the fabric and the skin is relatively large.
At this time, we may have to increase the number of friction.
Make the number of friction between the fabric and the skin relatively large.
Then it won't be relatively slippery.
It's easier for you to tie a knot.
This is what we often say.
To change the number of friction.
In order to prevent the fabric from slipping.
Yes.
So in conclusion,
only these few parameters will have a very big impact.
Yes.
The other parameters may have a smaller impact.
Although I don't really understand these parameters,
I have tried them myself.
In fact, the impact is not very obvious.
The most important thing is these parameters.
Yes.
As for the deformation rate,
the effect of these parameters is that
after the fabric and the fabric are sewn together,
the position of the seam line is the most obvious.
And this value is usually just one value, which is zero.
When these values, for example,
when the deformation rate is zero,
all the wrinkles on the seam line will appear.
Then when the deformation rate is 99,
all the wrinkles on the seam line will disappear.
You can imagine, for example,
a very soft skirt.
It's a very soft skirt.
Yes.
Even if there is a big difference in the seam line,
in real life,
it will use some strange...
Its length will be different.
Yes, when its length is different,
if the deformation rate is zero,
these wrinkles will remain.
But when the deformation rate is 99,
it will use a special technique in real life
to make these wrinkles disappear.
It's only the big wrinkles on the skirt.
Because of the length of the fabric,
these wrinkles will disappear.
So the deformation...
It's like stretching the gap between the two.
Yes, so the deformation rate...
In general,
when you make this kind of hard clothing,
it's hard to see the difference.
Yes.
When you make this kind of skirt,
it's easy to see the difference.
And then,
the deformation rate,
it's actually to control
the elasticity of the wrinkles.
For example,
if you decrease the deformation rate,
our usual wrinkles
may be 2 cm wide.
If you increase the deformation rate...
If you decrease the deformation rate,
the wrinkle may be
from 2 cm wide
to 1.5 cm wide,
or 1 cm.
And the internal damping
is used for animation.
It's the resistance.
For example,
some people want to make the effect of water
in MD.
So they want to increase the resistance.
Because the water...
The resistance is different from the air.
Yes, you can understand it that way.
That is to say,
its rebound is different from the air.
When the internal damping is higher,
it's like going into the water
to dance or something.
To dissolve in the water.
Yes, the resistance is higher.
But this function,
since it's useful,
there's another way to solve it.
It's to solve the vibration
in the animation process.
For example,
a skirt is very long.
When you run in the air,
the skirt will vibrate very strongly.
Yes, it will run slowly.
Yes, but if you increase the resistance,
it's like in the water.
The whole process is softer,
it's more relaxed.
It doesn't vibrate that much.
It's a bit like
vibration correction.
Yes, that's right.
In some software,
the brush stroke is smooth.
It's similar to ZB's vibration correction.
Yes, it's softer
and more stable
in animation simulation.
In fact,
ZB's most commonly used
is the first six.
Vibration correction,
vibration correction,
and so on.
I almost forgot
to mention
another very important
factor.
Conflict.
In fact,
if you want to make
very thin fabrics,
your conflict
can't be very high.
If it's very high,
the structure between the folds
is relatively large.
Yes.
It's not like a very thin fabric.
But if you want to make
very heavy clothes,
but if you adjust it to the head,
it will still stick together
and still feel very soft.
You can make the conflict
a little bigger.
The wavelength seems to be 2.5.
Yes, 2.5.
Yes.
It's a very thin fabric.
But if it's a very thin fabric,
you have to make it,
for example,
I might change it to 0
because I want it to stick together.
The conflict
is not only between the fabric
and the fabric.
It also affects
the conflict between the body.
Yes, yes.
The conflict between the body
and the foundation.
If I want to make
very thick clothes,
maybe 2.5
is quite a lot of space.
Yes.
So,
if you want to make
very thin,
very thick clothes,
like these thin gloves,
I might give you
the conflict directly.
Yes.
But it still
leaves some space in the middle.
It still leaves some space.
Yes.
Because there is a surface barrier
around the model.
The surface barrier
is the model to the board.
There is an air wall
around this model.
The thickness of the air
is the surface barrier.
And the conflict thickness of the board
is the air around the board.
The thickness of the air
is this thickness.
So,
it will show up
in the fold position.
Because the fold
is actually
a piece of fabric
folded in half.
And the width
of the fold
in the middle
will affect
the thickness
of the conflict
because
the thickness
of the conflict
is the air
around the board.
So,
this place
will get bigger
if it calculates
the air
twice.
Yes.
I think
the rest
doesn't matter.
This is just
an example.
Yes.
There is another
very important
thing
that I found
recently.
Because
now,
MG has a
similar
display state
like the one
shown here.
Yes.
Sometimes,
I used to find
that some folds
look pretty
and nice
in here.
But once
you fold
the ZB,
you will find
another state.
So,
many times
you have to
do and fold
the ZB again.
The ZB has
a single light
in here.
It should be
a state
of light
everywhere.
When you fold
the ZB,
you can see
the texture
is very thin
and the fold
is very shallow.
But when you fold
the ZB,
it is very deep
and thick.
So,
there will be
some error
and you have to
adjust it.
Now,
with this function,
I think
it will be
closer
to the speed
of solving
the problem.
This should
also affect
the speed
of solving,
right?
Yes.
Because
when we open
it,
our renderer
will become
a high quality
from
a normal
V-Ray
design.
So,
it will
affect
the speed
of solving
to a certain extent.
Yes.
So,
we can
solve
the problem
by calculating
the effect
after entering
the ZB.
For example,
the fold
behind me
seems to be
okay.
But when I open it,
I find that
the shadow
is very deep.
It won't work
after entering
the ZB.
If it is in the project,
it will be
difficult to
adjust it.
Another
problem is
that
there are
some
things
that need
to be
avoided.
For example,
the back space.
this one
here.
It has been
turned
many times
before entering.
This kind of
fold
will not work.
Because
if we look at it
visually,
it looks like
it is being
cut.
This fold
here
has
lost
some
thickness
and
the whole
piece of cloth
has lost
its connection
with
the fabric.
If we look
at it
from the
front,
it is
very
thin.
It is
very thin.
If we look
at it
from the
back,
it is
very thin.
The
back
is
very thin.
The
front
is
very thin.
The
back
is
very thin.
The
back
is very thin.
But in
some cases,
it has
become flat.
The
fabric has
lost
its
body
size.
We have
to avoid
this
reasonable
misunderstanding.
Although
this
situation
is
true,
we
may
deliberately
avoid
it.
Because
It will be more convenient.
If there is a floating space,
and you try to break through it,
you won't be able to turn to that angle.
It will be very troublesome.
And if you tie it on the back or move it,
if it is too deep,
this part and this part will be pierced.
Another one is the movement state.
As we just said,
we must avoid some movements that do not match the movement direction.
We have already talked about this before.
We have spent a lot of time on it, so I will quickly go over it.
There are also some points that need to be avoided.
We have talked about this a lot in the past.
There are some things we often talk about in art,
such as the symmetry, the X-shape,
and the repetition.
For example, this one here and this one here are repeated.
If they are in our real world,
we have to avoid them in our projects.
We have to find a way.
In the beginning,
when we were working on the board,
we used a completely symmetrical edge.
After that, the size and position of the board
were completely the same.
On the left and right sides,
there is a similarity.
On the left and right sides, it is also very similar.
Sometimes,
we have to make some intentional mistakes.
For example,
I will make it a little longer on this side.
So that it will create some
different sections on this side.
It will destroy their symmetry and perfection at the same time.
There are some points in Tai Chi that we deliberately make.
For example, the shoulders.
For example, if you want to make it have some folds,
if you want to make it have some folds,
but your board is too good,
perfect,
at that time,
you may need to deliberately make two sealed data.
In fact, I used to be very concerned about this data.
These two sides must be the same.
Sometimes we deliberately make some mistakes,
so that it,
so that the data is not the same.
If the two data are not the same,
then it will create some folds,
and then it will create some folds.
Sometimes there are no folds,
it is also because the board is too close to it.
It is too suitable,
so that there are no folds.
Yes, when I used to play board,
when I was in MD,
I had a very serious pressure.
Basically, all my sleeves here,
all of them are designed to be equal.
And the sides are the same.
And then I found that when I do this,
many users will ask,
why does this dress look like a line of sewing,
which is not very real.
And then I thought,
but I just follow the reality.
Then I thought,
oh, I understand.
Because even in real life,
there will be a lot of folds in these places.
There will be a lot of folds in the back.
Yes, because in real life, there will be folds,
There will be folds,
there will be a line.
Because in 3D, like in MD,
it's not...
Actually, we're just two panels.
It's sewn along a face.
But in real life,
this line,
when we sew clothes,
it's all sewn by a line.
The line itself will have some elasticity.
So if it's sewn in this way,
there will be some folds.
And then I also...
In real life,
the strength and density of its sewing
can't be done completely evenly in the software.
Yes, yes, yes.
It can't be done so mechanically.
It will naturally produce some folds.
Yes.
So sometimes I also deliberately divide a part of the sewing line
into three parts.
The first part may be A long B short,
and then the second part may be B long A short.
Yes, that's right.
Sometimes we still...
I mean, the last one needs to be avoided.
And then it's been a long time.
It's okay.
You can do it slowly.
Sometimes, for example, this sleeve,
there is a possibility that...
In real life,
if we measure it with the formula of clothing and furniture,
this person's sleeve may be...
For example, I'm 41 years old now.
He may be...
He should be 43 years old now.
But there is a problem with 43 years old.
There is a problem that
he may have a particularly strong pile.
In fact, there will be a kind of condensation.
So maybe sometimes in the process of making a sewing machine,
we have to deliberately reduce the amount of fabric in some places.
Because in real life, when we wear clothes,
the fabric is not stretched well.
So we have to leave some space for exercise.
But in our project,
in order to avoid this kind of space,
this imperfect visual effect,
we may deliberately modify it.
It's the same as just now.
We deliberately modify it.
We modify its size.
We don't want it to be too much.
We don't want it to leave so much space.
We want it to be some kind of...
As long as it's our standard,
it should be in line with our rules,
it doesn't need to be completely like in real life,
a space that is easy to leave for real exercise.
We want it to be a little flat.
We can't...
We don't want it to be too deep.
So that's the experience part.
I'll talk about this part first.
Because I don't want to take too long.
Next, I'll talk about some of my processes of getting into MD and ZB.
In the previous two videos,
I recorded a video.
Because I was thinking about fashion.
So I edited it.
This method, I actually didn't think about it for a long time.
This is actually not my method.
Because this is...
I also introduced it in the previous video.
It's about industrial engineering.
But I put it together with another method.
But now I see that people use this method a lot.
I wrote this tutorial a long time ago.
This is the tutorial.
If it's written in more detail,
I might not be able to explain it in the video.
I'll post it in the official group.
You can add it to your group.
This is the tutorial I wrote three days ago.
It should be written in great detail.
It can be done perfectly from this side to the other side.
It can be done from all sides,
but it also has a high-level model.
It's a breakthrough.
But this process has a fatal flaw.
As I just said,
you can't guarantee that the points between these two panels are completely the same.
You want to guarantee that they are completely the same.
You can only manually decode or manually modify them.
Why do we have to be consistent?
Actually, sometimes I'm forced to do this.
Or there's a problem.
If it's our panel,
let me give you an example.
If it can't be consistent,
what will happen?
I don't know.
I don't know it well.
It's not as simple as it sounds,
but don't worry.
If you have problems with it,
let me help you change it.
If it's unsustainable,
it's not as easy and it's not as practical.
It's not as easy as it sounds.
It's going to be very difficult.
But it's not.
If it's unsustainable,
it's not going to be very difficult.
I don't know.
I think the technique I used to use
when I was studying at high school,
It's like watching a teacher teach.
Especially when you were talking about the fold.
I think it's very useful, whether it's 3D or 2D.
I'm done. I don't think I have the file I used before.
It's okay.
I don't have it either.
It's easy to look at.
Let me find one.
I think I have two files.
A copy of the file was here.
It's a zoom file.
I think it's OK.
I have a copy file.
You say you have a copy file.
I have a copy file now.
You can see that it's a zoom file.
I'm going to send it to it.
Pretend it's the same copy file as this one.
You need to send it to the same place.
There it is.
and check if they are together or not.
In my case, all the panels are separated in this way.
Now, the point is that
no matter if you are using RuneMesh like this
or you are using a flat RuneMesh,
it can't be consistent.
So, I will make a default.
I will make a default.
Let's assume that it is like this.
I will raise a level.
Raise a level 4.
Let's push it back.
and then rise again and then fall back again.
There will be a big gap between the two panels.
If we don't merge these two panels together.
Because once you drop the level here,
and rise again, you will still have a chance.
The model will get smaller and smaller,
and the gap will get bigger and bigger.
In the future, we may have to spend a lot of time
on re-filling this gap.
It will take a lot of time.
It's not good.
You will have to learn it by hand.
I think it's a waste of youth.
And this process is just...
If you say you are a gamer,
you will have to go through it again.
It's okay.
But if you want to make a film,
or if you want to re-fill,
you have to re-fill all of these.
Otherwise, when you re-fill in the middle,
it will send you the opposite information.
If there is a gap in the middle,
it's a very bad situation.
I will stop here.
I will just show you a simple video.
Now I will put the UV on the U-shape.
Mr. A has shown this before.
I think many of you know about this.
Put it on the U-shape.
It's getting closer.
And then back to this side.
Actually, you can make one first.
Just put it on the body first,
and then make the board.
I forgot I made the screen first.
Then I will put the board there.
And then this is the joint or the non-joint.
Actually, both are fine.
I thought about it later.
The 2D board is of course non-joint.
The 3D board is actually joint or non-joint.
All are fine.
Why haven't I come yet?
This side is the other side.
This is a 2D version.
We need to get rid of the 3D one.
I think many of you know this.
But the one in the back is a little different.
I know the one in the back is different.
I have introduced it in another video.
But I don't think it has been finished yet.
So I will show it again.
In this state,
the point is completely visible.
So it can be HOUBIN or HOUBIN.
It can be HOUBIN in Maya as well.
The following is the same as the two UWINs.
Then I will convert the 2D version to ZB.
Automatically decode it.
So it can be HOUBIN like this.
The advantage of this method is that
it is basically a 4D script.
The bad thing about it is that
I have already shown it earlier.
It has a HOUBIN.
It can't be HOUBIN without a HOUBIN.
It is a game-like process.
If you want to make a film,
you need to do a calculation
or do a binding.
There is a possibility that
the HOUBIN will leak out as soon as you stretch it.
Yes.
Then I will use the original 3D version
to transfer the UV to the 2D version.
So I have fixed some points.
I want to make sure that
its scale is completely aligned.
Let me check its scale.
It is completely aligned.
Then I will use the 3D version
to make the HOUBIN.
I will use the original 3D version
to make HOUBIN.
Then I will use the original 3D version
to make the 3D version
to make the HOUBIN.
I will transfer it to HOUBIN
in the 3500-meter plus.
I have also changed this
other setting to
a rule.
Sometimes I don't use HOUBIN
just to transfer the UV,
I use the model coordinate to transfer it.
Sometimes I don't use HOUBIN
just to transfer the UV,
You can see that it is the same as before.
This one can be remodeled.
The triangle-shaped version.
Then we can use the plug-in.
I have already introduced this plug-in before,
so I won't talk about it here.
If any of you know about it,
you can check it out.
It is also available in Max.
I also saw a similar method in Max.
I will look for the link in the group later.
The above is the loss of high model,
loss of low model, division level,
and then the point loss.
Wait for a while.
It is growing.
It will produce a model.
The surface is very high,
but the advantage of this model is that
the details of MD are almost completely preserved,
there is no loss of details.
And the thickness has been added.
Then this model can be imported to ZB.
If you import it to ZB,
it will be completely independent like a real kernel.
And it has thickness and details.
Let me show you the details.
You can find the details here.
If you are playing games,
you need to calculate the size of the grid.
Calculate the size of the surface.
At this level,
you can use this model to modify it
to become the final decoding model.
From the beginning,
we have considered the final decoding stage.
Because I have to repeat the same process here.
So it is a bit difficult to decode.
This method is fine,
but the second method is especially difficult to decode.
I had to modify it for a long time.
.
It's almost done.
And now it's the same level.
There is a small tip.
If you directly import it to the decoding.
You can see that this grid is filled with Honeycomb.
Normally, when we have a direct decoding of Contrary D,
the grid doesn't show that much.
We make it lower to the lowest level,
and export it once.
You can export it to the outside.
Then you import it back in.
Then you upgrade it.
This web page becomes the most common one we have.
It doesn't really have a way out.
It is just a small trick.
The web page is getting thinner and thinner.
It is like a 1st, 2nd, 3rd.
It is getting thinner and thinner.
Then you can remove these.
Then you can start to carve.
But I think this is suitable for the game process.
If you are making a game or something,
it may not be good.
So I have another way.
This is a simple way to do it.
To put it simply,
you can just drag it out,
keep it in a UV group,
and it will pop out automatically.
The good thing about this is that
the clothes are a whole.
But the bad thing is that
it is not that perfect.
So both of these ways
have their drawbacks.
Of course, there will be a third way later.
You have to make a model that is horizontal.
You can make it horizontal from the outside.
Make it horizontal from here.
I will unlock the發現.
Because unlocking the發現 is
actually quite important here.
Because later I will use
a thing called a soft edge.
A concept to make it
choose a filter.
Now its UV is good.
Its UV is separated.
Now I need to select
all its UV borders.
Set it to a hard edge state.
It will look like this.
If it has a rechtance of 5, 6 grad levels,
it will look like this.
If the space is too small,
there will be a retentance.
If it is perfectly Multi-closed,
then there should be no such situation with 5, 6 grads.
I will select it now.
I think not everyone can see clearly.
I will first select a U-shaped edge point,
Let's change it to the line mode.
I will select the line mode again.
Then I will select the line on the right side.
I remember there was another way to do it faster.
But I forgot.
I will try it again.
This method is also fine.
Set it to the hard side.
I will open the hard side color.
Now the purple color is all on the hard side.
And these purple colors are just
an interface for my clothes.
But my goal is to keep the purple color
for my clothes.
I can use this.
This should be...
This interface should be used by many people.
Or it can be used in this YangHou.
It can also be used.
It can also be used in this YangHou.
Or it can also be used in this YangHou.
This is a very simple setting.
It is a very simple setting.
I will enter a number on it.
Then I will use the soft side here.
You can try other parameters.
The most important thing is to use the number on it and the soft side.
Then it will reset it for me once.
It will reset...
I just...
Because I set it too low.
It is too low.
The front side is also low.
I may set it a little higher.
It is not interesting to reset.
But this is...
My fabric is a little...
Because the red line here is a little...
It's been folded several times.
So it doesn't fit well.
If it were a more normal fabric,
it wouldn't have this kind of...
It wouldn't have this kind of...
It wouldn't be so messy.
It will be much better.
Because I want to keep it now.
Its point is...
The point is mixed together.
And I want to keep its cut line.
I want to keep its UV border.
Then the rest of the work is to fix some parts that are not very good.
I want to fix the line a little bit.
I want to fix it as much as possible as possible.
I made a mistake in the middle of the video.
It's gone.
It's the part where I fixed your face.
I don't know why.
I fixed it several times.
It's gone.
After fixing it...
Yes.
It's gone.
Maybe I made it too fast.
After fixing it, give it a UV.
Because if I don't fix it,
it won't keep the UV.
This step in ZB,
using ZRuby is the same.
The software is the same.
Now I have to filter the selection.
The filter selection is here.
Let me pause it for a moment.
Then I select the circle.
Then I select the edge.
Then I remove the edge.
I may have some kind of compulsion.
I have to keep the sewing line in the correct position.
Because these sewing lines can be tilted in ZB.
Of course, it's a different kind of brush.
But I still think...
It's better to plan it out.
If you list it in the plan,
and if you want to re-shape the panel,
you may have some problems.
I'll fill in the gaps.
If I miss something, I'll fix it.
This method is very simple.
The previous method is not important.
The important thing is to fix it later.
Everyone should know the previous method.
I'll fix it faster.
Then I can insert it into ZB.
Don't do it too fast.
I can do it in UV view.
I use a UV view group now.
It's the one I did before.
I'll do it again.
Use UV view group.
Here is the key point.
Let's use craze to lock in the so-called group border.
Then I'll give it a bevel.
But my bevel is only 2.
2 is too low.
I suggest you use 4.
Why is 2 too low?
You'll see later.
What's the consequence of 2?
The bevel will be triggered as soon as you input the number.
It will trigger according to your group border.
It will make sure that all the interfaces have been beveled.
Then I'll cancel all of them.
I'll cancel all of my craze.
All of them.
Then I'll make all of my models a group.
I'll make a new group.
The accounting key is ctrl-w.
The accounting key of the group is ctrl-w.
Then I'll call craze again.
The border of craze.
I'll call craze again.
Because it will only enter the open border of craze.
Enter the border of craze.
Now all of my borders are kept.
If I delete them, it's no problem.
This one seems to have been quickly entered.
After keeping the border of craze, I'll delete it.
How many times have I deleted it?
5 times.
I'll record the merge first.
Then I'll put the other model that was directly generated from AMD next to it.
Then I'll import the details back.
I have taken notes of all of these details.
But there is one more problem.
It is not thick enough.
If you use ZB you know,
If you use ZB, once you squeeze out,
you may lose the level.
Once you have the level, you can't squeeze it out.
The water and the fire cannot coalesce.
Those two things cannot be done simultaneously.
So if you need to squeeze out from a lower level,
You may lose the element of AMD.
If you used a higher level, you may lose the element of AMD.
If you squeeze it out, it will not be able to go back down.
It will not be able to change. This is also very troublesome.
This is a contradiction that cannot be solved.
I will solve it now.
Because I saw a ZB plug in the previous A站.
It has already solved this problem perfectly.
I will fix it now.
There is a plug in the previous A stand.
I can show you the plug in the previous A stand.
If you are interested, you can support me.
I will look for my face list.
I have already bought the main board.
This one.
Squeeze it out and keep it in the back.
It can make your model...
Let me pause it for a while.
You can see it.
It can keep your model in the back.
But it will squeeze out the back again.
The principle is to squeeze it out directly.
After squeezing it out, it will delete it.
This is the principle.
But it will automatically change.
Yes.
Let me install the plug-in.
Let's use it again.
There is little plug-in parameter on the top.
It is just the thickness.
How many are there?
Is it outwards?
No, just this one.
Click it and it works.
Now we have both the thickness and the texture.
The texture is there and so is the thickness.
This solves the problem of the thickness.
It is not good to use an emitter in a real-time project.
It is inconvenient to use the method or to make a tutorial.
There is not much content in the back.
I will make another tutorial to solve this problem.
That's it.
There is a third method.
I didn't record this video.
The third method is what we talked about at the beginning.
It is an emitter of MD.
I think it is a bit difficult to use now.
The most important thing to note about this emitter is
that the points between the sleeve and the panel
must be completely aligned.
Not completely, but the number of points must be consistent.
Only in this way will the meaning of the emitter be there.
Now I will show you.
I will show you my clothes first.
I will make a piece.
This is the ultimate solution.
This is not very useful at the moment.
I will not draw it.
I will draw it.
It does not matter.
This is a possibility.
If you are using AMD's top-hood,
you can see that my top-hood has very little surface area.
The important thing is to keep the points corresponding to each panel.
We don't want to use a perfect grid to wrap it up.
Because this can be divided.
See, it can be divided.
This side can be divided.
The back side can also be divided.
After it is divided, it will be wrapped up.
So we don't have to worry about how much surface area we have.
The important thing is to keep the points corresponding to each other.
Another advantage is that after it is divided,
it will stay on the top of the panel.
I will make the bottom part
into a model.
I will make it into a model.
Now my model is ready.
It has become a model.
I will make two more parts.
Make it into a model.
And make it into a model.
ss
Now I choose the Temporal March panel.
I remember that it would repeat on this panel.
This must be a problem with the monoclonal membrane.
In the code, I found what I just saved.
What was my name again?
ShirtHiMD.
I can't find it.
Right now, this point is not completely correct.
Actually, I have a very quick way to find it.
Let me separate it first,
and then I will show all the edges.
For example, this edge here,
it's not completely correct.
There are some places where it's wrong.
Here, it's wrong.
Let me fix it.
I select all the edges here.
All the open edges.
And then,
I don't need to delete these open edges.
I use...
Oh, this is not exactly the same.
Let me fix this.
How come it's still wrong?
I can't find the wrong way.
It's probably because the protoboard is messed up.
Maybe it's because of the top plate.
The top plate has a bent edge.
It's messed up.
Cut off the parts that don't need to be cut off.
Use a bridge.
This is a bridge.
Bridge.
Cut off the parts that don't need to be cut off.
Now we have a perfect line.
This sleeve is also a hard edge.
The UV may be damaged.
If there is no UV, we will give it a flat surface.
I will do it again.
Select the edge.
Switch to the edge mode first.
Here.
Select the edge.
Next.
Select the hard edge.
Select.
It will only select the hard edge.
I will close it and reset it.
In the UV window.
Cut it off.
OK.
Now I have my UV and my board.
My interface is in the right place.
I will repeat what I did earlier.
I will try to do it again.
Faster.
id
Here.
Faster.id
Now I am using the craze.
And upgrade it.
Let's upgrade it.
I should first...
There is a problem here.
If it is a single version, a complete version,
it will not be able to play with Beowulf.
It may have to play manually.
Let's try again.
Let's upgrade it first.
Let's upgrade it.
Yes, that's right.
If it doesn't play, let's upgrade it manually.
This one.
Okay, I have already upgraded it.
Of course, the face is very low.
Then I will...
I will upgrade it.
I might be a little dizzy, so I will upgrade it a few times.
I saw someone in the chat asking if you guys can understand.
And then someone fell asleep.
It's a little...
I also think it's pretty clear.
And then our control room was here just now.
And then...
This is probably going to be added to Maya first.
Let's add a little more.
And then...
Change our model.
I'll have to redo it later.
Actually...
I have to keep up with my details.
And then I'll play it again.
Okay.
If I can see the style, then it is fine.
Because at the time, I was going to do...
Make a new model.
And if my method was to make a gap...
But when you make a gap,
it will be projected into a screen.
So let's put this gap in first.
And then we can switch it on.
I think the operation failed.
Oh, my level...
I like the time of the roller coaster.
I just clicked the wrong button.
The model I originally created on MD
made a conflict with the original model.
So, the model is now in a conflict with the original model.
The model I originally created on MD made a conflict with the original model.
If the model wasn't in the middle,
the red line would have been here.
This wasn't done well.
The dress might have been better.
The operation I did earlier was too fast.
The most perfect state of the collider is
the most important thing.
This piece should be added.
Then we use theEst dönere .
Then we use theEst döner .
The costume on the Est döner is 10 meters long.
Él noisi
An Instagram post,
The background is too thin, but there is already a background.
Let me push it a little bit.
The background is too thin.
In this case,
we have all the effects we want.
I didn't do it very carefully.
I just wanted to demonstrate the principle.
It's okay.
The atmosphere is also there.
The network is also square.
My cutout is also in the correct position.
I have everything I want.
The only hope is that
the top will be easier to use.
It will be more realistic.
We are also thinking about how to solve the problem of the top.
Because the top we are currently developing,
what we want to solve is that
when we use a retop,
the points on the side can align with each other.
This is what we want to deal with now.
Because if we do it ourselves,
when you modify the top,
the other side will also align with each other.
This is a problem we currently want to solve.
Because if we can do this,
the top will be more convenient.
I have already copied it.
That's all for my presentation.
Okay.
Now we can ask the teacher a question.
Do you have any questions?
Yes, if you have any questions,
you can ask any questions related to software.
You can ask Xue Yidada.
Yes.
I may not be very proficient in software.
After all, the official staff is here.
I can't answer the questions in front of the audience.
No, no.
If you have questions about AMD,
I will have a simple demonstration later.
You can ask me when I demonstrate.
I am not able to hear you.
The hands are usually ...
You speak.
It's okay, you can speak first.
He said the hands are usually hand-picked.
When is it usually done?
If your separet is right.
The hands will be implemented naturally.
Of course, if you want to make it moreidelicated,
the hands are still there.
This is an experience thing.
You can't solve it by formula.
I'm not the boss, I'm the one cleaning the toilet.
If you are interested, you can check it out.
The official website should have some information about it.
You can check it out.
There is also an account on Bilibili.
Many clothes are very difficult to wear together.
There is an account on Bilibili.
But if you want them to collide with each other,
you can't do anything about it.
You can just put it back together like this.
It won't work.
This way, they won't participate in the calculation.
If they can freeze it,
they will still collide.
If there are many layers,
and the configuration is poor,
you can only do as I did before.
At the beginning,
you can make it 15 or 20.
You have to be very careful with every step.
Make sure it's big.
Make sure it's big or small.
Keep making it smaller and smaller.
Don't make it too small.
Make it bigger and smaller.
There is a problem with layers.
It's...
Let me look at this again.
It's not the same as before.
I just made the top.
Let me answer.
I just saw that
there is a problem with MD animation.
There is a problem with MD animation.
Sometimes it's because
you use layers.
There are many people
who think that
layers are always kept.
For example, the outer layer is 2
and the inner layer is 1.
In the animation process,
because one material
has a positive and a negative side,
when we identify layers,
we usually use the back of one material
to identify the positive side of another material.
For example, the collar.
Sometimes the collar is facing the back.
When you use layers,
it may have some
differences with other places.
So in the animation process,
you have to
make sure that you use
the finished quality model,
which is the red double arrow.
I just saw a friend
asking about the animation model.
Because I think the GPU model is faster,
can I use the GPU model
when recording an animation?
The answer is no.
If you use the GPU model,
because it's unstable when recording an animation,
there will be some problems with
layer identification,
so there will be differences.
I usually use the
upper and lower layers
to add layers.
Once I have the right
resolution,
I will add the layers.
There is a blue line
that looks uncomfortable.
Oh, I see.
The reason I
put the memory back to zero
is because I'm not used to
seeing the blue line.
The blue line, yes.
Also,
if it's already correct,
there will be a natural
gap between the original
and the original version.
Oh, yes.
I saw a comment saying
to use the storage mode.
Oh, that's what you were talking about.
This problem needs to be fixed now.
The storage mode leads to
the MD animation error
is because in the old version,
the real number calculation
of MD and other software
is different.
In the process of
the real number calculation,
for example,
a few thousand frames
will be less than a few frames
in the MD,
and then there will be
this deviation,
which is different.
And this problem
should have been fixed
in the MD.
Another problem
is that there is no problem
in the MD.
So,
I saw that
when making military equipment,
the knee is breathable,
and there is a gap
in the calculation.
If the knee is breathable,
it should be moved in the model form.
Now the model can be moved.
Yes.
It was not convenient
to move it in the old version.
A few days ago,
I solved a problem of a friend.
I wanted to make a tree waist,
which is the tree waist
used in Japanese clothing.
The tree waist is an animation
for the tree waist.
I hope that the equipment
can participate in the animation all the time,
and that the fabric
is between the equipment
and the human body.
If you want to make such an animation,
I think
you can put a transparent
board outside
to make a constraint.
After making a constraint
on the clothing,
for example,
there are some fabrics.
For example,
the conflict between the study room
and the fabric is different.
The leather is a hard fabric,
like a steel ring
outside the clothes.
The steel ring itself
is not easy to be influenced by the outside world
to make changes.
But the study room
is easy to be influenced by the outside world.
For example,
when I make a constraint
on a piece of fabric,
I will put a layer of fabric on the outside.
For example,
the leather is fixed
so that this area cannot move.
Then I set the transparency
of the fabric to 0,
so that there will be a constraint.
I did it like this
when I gave it to him.
When there is a transparent
sheet like this,
I will put a layer of fabric on it.
For example,
the armor,
the waist,
and so on.
Because many of my friends
want to wear it
when they make animation.
I usually
I think I posted a video
about sewing in the group.
It's a very amazing method.
I cut the sleeves
directly.
I will give them
a different tail shrinkage.
The inside layer
I put it in at the end.
For example,
the sleeves
will be divided into three sections.
Then I may
put the most close
to the outer layer
I will give it
a very large shrinkage.
For example,
I may use 120 or 130.
Then it will get bigger.
Then I will continue to
shrink it.
Yes, continue to shrink it.
After that,
I will change the shrinkage
to 100.
Then the sleeves
will be rolled up.
For these,
if you want to learn
these little tricks,
you can add us in the Q&A group.
I usually
I will record the video
for you guys
in the Q&A group.
You can ask me
if you want these videos.
Now,
you can ask
some questions
about Yang Da.
I will answer the questions
about MD later.
Because there is still
a part of me.
No,
I will take a long time.
I will try to speak faster.
I'm sorry.
You can't easily
get the right answer
in the Q&A group.
In fact,
it's still
a question from the video.
Yes.
Sometimes I feel
that in the Q&A,
we need to
go a little bit higher.
We may need to
increase this part
a little bit
I've tried two ways to do it.
One is to choose a small line from the bottom of the down part and pull it with a spring.
Because there is a force in the middle, and the whole area is opened, it will be shrunk like this and a fold will be formed.
Another way is to use some of the down part of the cross section.
When using the down part of the cross section, the cross section is tight.
Then I use the down part of the cross section to press it with the down part of the cross section.
In this way, it is equivalent to saying that I let the cross section have a shrinking force here, and then I let the down part have more fabric.
Then it will also have that effect.
Yes, it is quite difficult here.
I didn't do it well either.
It's a bit of a headache for me to do it here every time.
In the previous session, did I post a video?
I think I did.
Oh, I don't think I did.
I used to play games.
Now I play games.
Do you have any questions for Yang Da?
If you have questions about MD, you are welcome to add us at any time.
Yes, I usually answer questions and make teaching videos in the group during work hours.
I usually answer questions and make teaching videos in the group during work hours.
Can I rotate the board?
Yes, you can.
You can rotate the board.
Wait a minute, let me take a look.
If I can...
Because it's a coincidence.
It's a coincidence.
Wait a minute.
I cut my...
For example, I now have a board.
If you want to rotate a single line, you have to use the edit dot line tool.
Select it and then rotate it.
There will be a live broadcast today.
Let me find the sentence.
Can I go back now?
You can go back now.
Oh, that's fine.
Then I can start preparing my Google.
I'll be here.
I'm done.
I'll see you after the session is over.
Yes.
Okay.
Okay, I can...
Oh, Yang Da is here.
Don't say it like Yang Da has left the line.
He is here.
You can ask me any questions during the process.
Let me find it.
I have a video ready.
This time I want to show you a set of...
It's a bit like an assassin's costume.
It's a bit like an assassin's suit.
The entire cost is not that long.
It's mainly a follow-up operation.
For example, before I make a suit,
I don't dress up myself either.
I usually either search online...
I forgot to talk about it earlier.
I definitely don't recommend that new students dress up themselves.
Yes.
Even if we have been learning the board for many years,
I don't know how to do it myself. It's too tiring to do it myself.
Usually it's either directly on Pinterest or Baidu to search for the board.
Other than that, I would probably just pull a default board from our library
and then use the automatic adjustment board tool to make it match with the body first.
After the adjustment is done, for example, when I can't match the clothes I'm making now,
I'll open a transparent map and then I'll draw a line along the character's curve.
This way I have a reference.
For example, for the waist, I want it to be tighter.
How do you determine if the clothes you're making are voluminous or not?
First, you have to make the clothes bigger.
Since you want to make them voluminous,
you can just drag and drop them to the bottom.
You can just use the fabric to stack them.
Or something like that.
And then when I see the transparent map,
I think the waist needs to be adjusted here.
If you want to make a board reference, you can just go to Baidu and search for the board number.
Or there's another way.
You can just buy a board that's made by someone else and change it.
This way the entry point is lower.
The entry point is lower.
I think it's actually the most convenient to change someone else's clothes.
Because there are still automatic wear and adjustment boards now.
As long as you can determine the right size,
it's more convenient.
Or just make it look good.
Generally speaking, just make it look good.
Just make the clothes look good.
You don't have to worry about whether the board is right or wrong.
Yes, it must look good in the project.
But in actual clothing design,
you have to be flexible and comfortable.
Yes.
But sometimes people will say,
why are my clothes not stable?
Many times when I check the clothes,
it's because they're too tight.
And when I open the pressure map,
it's all red.
At this time, I'll ask the women in the group,
please take care of our model.
Don't let them wear clothes that are too tight.
You can often see the stretch in the order period.
Yes.
You have to be careful.
It's best to avoid some red parts.
Because this kind of part,
the stretch is very serious.
The grid of that part is very deformed.
Secondly, it is easy to cause instability.
When doing some special actions,
for example, some people may have to record an animation in MD.
It's easy to cause some instability.
The reason why this material library is so rich
is because this is MD10.
This is the new version,
the new material added.
Of course, if you usually want us to add
some random material at home,
you can ask us about it.
Just give us feedback.
We may also prepare some.
Also, like the previous live broadcasts,
I used to do live broadcasts.
I uploaded some of those clothes
to the MD store.
It's the MD mall.
Yes, you can download it.
The clothes I made for live broadcasts
are usually free.
So you can download it.
There are some bags and scarves in it.
You can reuse them.
Which version is better?
I will definitely say the latest version is better.
How can I tell you
which version is better?
How much is this MD?
Personally,
it seems to be $2,016 a year.
But we usually have a lot of events.
There is also a discount for black dance.
You can buy it when it's black dance.
Or if you have a student ID,
there is a discount for three years.
These are all available.
Also, we usually do some activities.
You can also participate in some draw.
Something like that.
Please pay attention to me.
Yes.
What is the relationship
between the embroidery hole and the sleeve?
I can't get a good connection
with the gauze.
This can be seen.
It should be the introduction of new features
or something like that.
Oh my god, there are too many chats.
Let me see.
I will do the curve part first.
Then I will connect the sleeves.
After the curve is done,
I will do the sleeves.
Then I will connect the sleeves.
Yes.
I was like this before.
I also told you in the previous reference video.
You have to do the gauze first.
When the sleeve opens,
it's not so tight.
When it fits the human body,
you have to do the sleeves again.
Then it will be more correct.
You told me in the chat
that you want to do the white-skinned MD.
Be careful.
I've already stared at you.
Yes.
It's dangerous.
Then this speech.
It's hard to grasp the shape of the sleeve.
The easiest way is to use a ruler
to tilt it in the opposite direction.
It's not convenient.
Then when I make clothes,
for example,
it's very tight in the front.
I might add a point to it.
Add a line.
Because of the line,
everyone can do a joint in the later stage.
In other software,
you can erase this seam.
Erase.
Yes, erase.
Then with the ruler,
you can make the clothes fit the human body quickly.
Because the ruler
will lack a triangular area.
It can still be,
especially when we make clothes
for some female characters.
Because women's bodies are very thin.
Yes, the waist is very thin.
Then the chest is relatively large.
Then the structure like this,
we will definitely use the ruler.
Because the ruler is a triangle.
It digs out a triangle.
You can understand that
the waist is a lot smaller.
Then the collar is made.
When we make the collar,
we can jump here.
Then when we make the collar,
I want to make a folding collar for it.
But if I directly extend the collar of the folding collar,
it will be interlocked with the body.
But once the clothes are interlocked with the body,
if you simulate it again,
it will be difficult to drag the collar.
So,
generally speaking,
I will first reduce it.
It has a golden shrink rate.
You can look here.
I have reduced its golden shrink rate.
Then its collar will shrink.
After the collar shrinks,
I will manually stretch the collar.
Just try to avoid the model having an interlock.
Then when the simulation is stable,
I will change the shrink rate.
There seems to be an offline WeChat group.
But this WeChat group is not very useful.
Very few WeChat groups can support it.
Because WeChat is not very convenient to support.
Then...
Oops.
Is my mic too low?
Wait a minute.
I will turn the volume down.
I ate too spicy yesterday.
As a result,
my voice became mute today.
Then...
When we make the collar,
you can see that
my collar is actually curved.
It's not a...
It's not straight.
Yes, it's not straight.
Because...
Because when we make the board,
the top of the body is curved.
Then the collar also has to have a certain curve.
And when making this kind of curve,
there is actually a basic rule.
It's like this corner.
When making the board,
try to make it a straight corner.
Because when we make a straight corner,
when we put the two boards together,
it's a flat corner.
It won't have a protruding point.
There will be a gentle edge.
Yes.
So...
Because if you think about it,
if these two lines are all straight lines,
it will be closer to V.
So we will...
We will be able to adjust it manually.
The next step is to make a sleeve.
After that,
I will start to think about this.
I want to make a sleeve.
If you want to make this kind of tight structure,
I usually draw it directly on the model.
I won't search on the Internet
how to make the board.
Yes, you can.
You select a board and right-click
to reset the 2D arrangement position.
That is to restore the 2D plane.
And then draw a line on the model.
We can't talk about this function
in every live broadcast.
Because this function is often used.
Especially when making some tight structures,
or when you are not sure
what kind of structure the board looks like,
you usually draw it manually.
Then...
I think 2D operations
need a better logic.
So it won't be messy.
3D operations will be more straightforward.
For example,
you made a curved line, right?
Yes.
The curved line of the model is usually in MD.
This sliding line is not a new function of MD10.
This seems to be a new function of MD8.
Yes, this function is indeed
more suitable for tight structures.
For example, I will use it
when I make this kind of tight vest.
And also when I make some braids,
or something that is more tight.
I will use it often.
And this function...
The most used tutorial video
can be seen from the last episode
when I made braids.
In the previous episode,
I basically used this function all the time.
Because braids...
It's not realistic to make straight boards.
Because braids are very special.
In real life,
the braids of braids
are sometimes rectangular.
Very abstract.
It's very flexible.
Yes.
And then it might be
a rectangular shape
on a person.
And then it becomes another shape.
And then...
Anyway, when I wear layers,
I might choose to use the function
of freezing and anti-activation.
I will freeze the inner layer
and then use the layer layer
on the outer layer
to wear the clothes out.
Let me see.
Here seems to be the back...
Oh, when I freeze,
I feel like this kind of bottom-down position,
you must give it this...
Try to stretch it a little wider.
Because if it is very narrow,
it will actually stretch to the horizontal direction.
Its curve is not a straight curve.
It will extend to the sleeve.
This kind of extension is not very good.
And it will actually affect the wear.
If you want the board to fit your body completely,
you can't just use fixed pressure.
You can also...
First, you have to reduce the surface stiffness.
You can't let the air around the model
be too thick.
And then...
This...
The curve of the board...
And what else?
You have to try to fit the body.
But in fact,
the simplest thing is
you just draw on the body.
Oh, I'm not particularly anxious.
I'm just talking about
how fast you can do it.
You can check out the tutorial video
on how to cross the board.
And then...
Let me think about it.
What am I doing now?
Oh, I'm just fixing the curve.
The operation is too fast.
Every time we do a live stream,
we will put the tutorial video
in the PR of the video.
Yes, Xuezi will talk about it today.
We will put the complete version
in the PR of the video
and the tutorial video with subtitles.
If the live stream speed is too fast,
you can choose to watch that version.
If you want to learn again later,
or follow our steps,
you can watch that version.
And in that version,
we will also write the principle in it.
Today's video will also have
the home version.
It's a trouble to play God's Day.
If you play God's Day,
you have to use a fixed needle all the time.
A few days ago,
in the group chat,
I was like...
Did I put that video in?
I seem to have forgotten.
It's a video of God's Day.
Basically,
you have to use a lot of fixed needles.
You can also do it in 3D software
and use UV to make the model
into a template.
And then...
Here...
During the process,
I will probably change the posture.
After changing the posture...
Oh, I saw the chat saying
to do the breast massage, right?
Then you can watch the last episode of the live stream.
Not the last episode,
but the last episode of the live stream.
Because if you want to match the shape of the breast,
you have to make some adjustments to its physical properties.
But in the process of making clothes,
I will occasionally choose
to change the model's posture.
Because you have to make sure
that the clothes look okay
in different postures.
Although we...
What Mr. Yang said
is a little different.
In MD,
I will probably look at
some of his movements.
Because this may affect
people who make animation.
Will there be any problems
during the animation process?
Because you have
a complete logic solution.
Yes.
The model that is outside,
there is animation.
If you go to the Olympic Games,
you can bring animation.
FBX can also bring animation.
And then if the animation
is not done in MD,
you can go and have a look.
We have a video tutorial
on animation.
It's very simple.
It's the entry level.
I want to see what I'm doing behind here.
I think the sleeves
are too loose.
And then the sleeves and the clothes
are a little
loose.
So I'm going to
adjust the width
of the sleeves.
For example,
when I'm making
this kind of flat
vest,
I will use
this kind of leather
fabric
to maintain
its shape.
Let me
show you
what I'm doing
behind me.
Here it is.
Because when you
make animation,
like leather fabric,
it is very
flexible.
It's very flexible.
You will see
that it's very
flexible.
And then
it's very
flexible.
But ultimately,
I will use
the enamel
to
tie
this
shoulder strap
here
with other
fabrics.
After the
wrong
youtube
I will
die of
illness.
So it will not
move
anymore.
After
see
This is a video.
Video?
It should be called virtual idol.
Oh, I'm not sure about that.
If you don't want the fabric to be stretched and deformed,
it's better to use a different method.
For example, you can use a virtual model.
Or you can use a hardware setting that we shared in the group.
It says that H can make the fabric harder.
Next is making the pants.
For making the pants,
I actually try to change the shape of the pants by myself.
I usually don't change the shape of the pants at once.
I usually change the shape of the pants one by one.
For the belt,
I will use the same method,
which is to measure the waist of the virtual model.
When do you add a set of professional basic standards?
No.
I don't think we have any.
Because for the standard clothing,
there will be some teaching videos in the manual.
And then,
these teaching videos will have previews.
These previews can be downloaded.
Of course, it may require magic online.
If you want to learn magic online,
you can go to YouTube.
Every video will have a downloadable file.
And then,
I want to see where I'm talking about.
And then I will make a belt.
I will create a symmetrical version.
This is the waist of the model I measured.
And then,
the position I just measured may be relatively low.
And then I will change it again.
This is the whole size of it.
And then it's the same.
Like the belt here,
I may also make a curve for it.
How do you use the costume simulation in Maya and UU?
Generally, it's straight to...
Anyway, what I encounter seems to be straight to Alembic.
And then...
Here is the shape of the pants.
I usually change it.
And then I add a belt.
And then I may...
Because before,
to make the simulation faster,
I reactivated all the other parts.
Yes.
After the activation,
the simulation will be faster.
And then...
Because for reference,
I may show these clothes.
And then take a look at my pants.
Does it match?
If it doesn't match,
I may make other changes.
For example,
open a transparent picture and take a look.
This pants...
Is there a problem?
Actually, when I was making clothes,
I didn't think about it from the beginning.
What kind of clothes should I make today?
What about the activation and the freeze?
The freeze version
will have a mutual collision with other fabrics.
But the activation does not.
The activation does not directly calculate any collision.
And then the version will not make any deformation.
It's because of this characteristic.
It's just...
When you reactivate the version,
the operation speed of your computer will be faster.
Because directly in the 3D space,
these versions will be ignored.
They don't calculate any other collision.
Because what affects your computer operation speed
is the collision between these vertices and vertices.
What to do with the fold part of the worker?
Adjust it with a fixed needle.
And then do those folds.
When you do the fold,
usually,
you will first
harden the sheets.
Let these folds stack up,
and then sew them.
It will be more convenient.
Because...
Because if you fold the sheets
and sew them at the same time,
then it will produce some
arched folds,
or knurled folds.
It's a thread in the fold part.
This is something we used to do
when we did Japanese fashion.
Because in Japan,
they really like to do
knurled folds,
or foldable folds.
We have some examples of this.
This one is a little bigger than Hana's chest.
Hana's size can't be adjusted.
After that,
I made a tight...
pants.
I wanted to...
Because I wanted to...
I originally wanted to do
a pair of trousers.
I feel like
the trousers of the trousers
are more tight.
It doesn't seem to be
very loose.
So I adjusted it
to a tight pair of pants.
After that,
here,
I used a ruler.
I added some creases
to the bottom.
But I didn't add any
very obvious creases here.
Because in general,
it's still a tight pair of trousers.
When I was doing my swimsuit last time,
the live broadcast room was closed.
And when it was closed,
I was still very depressed.
At first,
Hana warned me.
I said,
it shouldn't be a big problem.
When I was doing it,
would I calculate the size of the thread?
I don't seem to...
I don't seem to calculate these things.
I just...
In the past,
I would let the two threads match first.
Now,
I just let it be like this.
It should be about the same.
The elastic band effect of Sondina is okay.
This was mentioned
in our previous live broadcasts
or when we were doing some trousers on the official website.
And then...
Look.
And then,
I used layers
to identify
the parts of these clothes.
The parts of the clothes.
As long as you apply the correct layer to the version,
you can change the layer.
For example,
I was here.
I remember when I was doing this project,
I forgot.
I forgot about this thing.
And then,
there seemed to be some problems afterwards.
If the internal thread is not sharp,
there is a method.
That is to say,
just like we said before,
CPU simulation
will slow down your computer operation speed.
We may finally choose to
delete the internal thread
when the particle diameter is particularly small.
For example,
when it is 5 or 3,
delete the internal thread.
Then,
double-click to simulate.
In this way,
it will be more natural
to say that it is too much.
And then,
it is because of the computer card
that it can be simulated slowly.
The effect may be better.
Otherwise,
if it is like GPU simulation,
you may lose that fold
at once.
Here,
I am cutting the card
for this card.
Basically,
this is
what everyone has seen before.
Just draw the internal thread
and cut it.
Then,
adjust the seam line.
Actually,
during the process of recording,
I have no idea
what kind of clothes
I am going to make.
I just do
what I like to do.
This suit is very sexy.
If you like it,
I can post it
in the community.
If you like it,
you can take it
and use it.
But,
there was a funny incident.
Someone
took my clothes
and put them
on the official website.
Then,
after changing the color,
they re-posted it
on our official website
in their own name.
They thought
we wouldn't see it
or something.
When I saw
this suit
being posted,
I thought
this is not
what I used to do
in the past.
So,
I just
cancelled it
and didn't
post it
on the website.
I didn't expect
it to be something
that I was
testing myself.
Then,
oh,
here,
I want to make
a bag for her.
So,
I cut it first.
Then,
I start to draw
the internal thread
and make
the bag for the clothes.
Then,
I want to make
a cover
that goes
through
two panels
or something.
Because
if I just
look at it,
I don't know
how long
it is.
So,
I will use
the basic length.
It shouldn't be here.
It should be
on the other side.
So,
I reacted
when I chose it here.
It seems that
it's not opened
by accident
in MD.
So,
I went to look for it.
In the 2D window,
you can see
the distance between
the two points.
After measuring,
you can draw the panels
according to this distance.
It will be more accurate.
In the past,
sometimes,
I used
the experience
to draw.
For those who
don't have
any idea
about the size
of the clothes,
you can measure
the distance between
the two points
and then
make the cover.
Because
this function
is hidden.
So,
some of you
may not know
that
this function
can be used
to make
a band.
When you make
a band,
you should pay attention
that
I will divide
the band
into two parts.
One part
is
shown
by this
band.
The other part
is below it.
In fact,
it is
two
large
bands
and
there is
a button
in the middle
to close it.
But,
if I make it,
I will just
cut it off.
Because
the key point
of making clothes
is not to make
what you can't see.
Yes,
make a fake one.
If you make
two parts,
it will be
very troublesome.
Yes,
it will be
very troublesome.
So,
I will make
a fake one
and look at it.
It will be
effective.
Also,
you must
remember
to make
a smaller
band
because
it will be
not smooth.
Then,
just
paste it.
In fact,
I have a problem here.
I didn't feel it
when I was making it.
Then,
when I finished making it,
I found that
why didn't I
make one
and then
make another one?
When I was making it,
I made two parts separately.
Then,
I made
a copy.
Sometimes,
when we make buttons,
we can just
make a copy.
But,
most of the time,
you can't make
a model
because
it's not
in the right size.
When it's not in the right size,
you can change it
with your model
or
it's just
a simple
simulation.
Then,
it will be
a problem.
So,
I chose
to
draw a
button
with
a board.
If you have
this kind of
hardware,
you can
make it
in the form
of your model.
Then,
it will
have a
collision effect.
Here,
I drew it
directly with the board.
Then,
I will
modify
its physical properties
into
harder physical properties.
The first six
are
the six physical properties
that Mr. Yang
just mentioned.
For example,
the bending strength
and the fineness.
I changed them
to 99.
It's a
very hard board.
You can see
that it will have
a very hard collision
and its shape will not change.
If you pull it,
it won't change much.
It's a
simple
package.
Then,
I will make
shoes.
For shoes,
I will
first
shrink
the
length
of the
pants
to make it
tight.
Because,
if you want to
make a board
outside,
like
every time
I make a board
outside,
I will
shrink
the
length
to make it tight.
This way,
it's more convenient
to wear it.
Then,
I will draw
a square board.
Because,
like shoes,
if you search online,
it's not necessarily
easy to find
the information
on the board.
I usually
draw it
by hand.
After
placing the
long-sleeve board
on the side,
you can
open the transparent cloth,
right?
When you open
the transparent cloth,
you can draw
along
the curve.
However,
when you draw,
you can't draw
along the curve
of the leg.
Because,
the human body
is
this,
it's three-dimensional.
It's not...
You have to wrap it around.
Yes,
you have to
put the amount
of the
amount
If you don't want to do it, you can do it with the default material, but the default material is a bit soft, so the fold will look a little bit too soft.
Then it's the same, you can reduce the particle diameter, and so on.
I didn't make the sole of the shoes here.
I usually adjust the curve of the front of the shoe to match the virtual model first,
then I will make the base of the shoe.
I will compare the effect of the 3D window and adjust the other curves at the same time.
In general, the leather fabric does not have any fine creases,
and it is more suitable for making accessories such as boots and gloves.
After I think the curve fits the human body, I will start to draw the bottom of the shoe.
If you are not familiar with the bottom of the shoe, you can use the same method.
Draw a rectangle first, then draw a transparent curve along the transparent curve.
If it is me, I will draw it by hand, because I know what it looks like.
Then I will unfold it and arrange it.
When I arrange it here, it does not roll up.
When you arrange it, you can also do it like this.
I will drag the flat part of the shoe over here.
I'm lazy here.
I put it in the arrangement point, which is closer to the bottom of the shoe.
After arranging, I will adjust the size of the shoe.
When I adjust the size, I will compare the length of the shoe on both sides.
You can see that the toes are easy to get pierced.
There is no problem with these piercings.
Also, you can see that when making boots, I am using leather fabric, right?
Although the leather fabric does not have a big fold, it looks very good.
But it is at the bottom of the foot, or it is a little bit like this.
Because our foot, you can see that its foot is like this.
Then it will be slightly curved and then protrude out.
When you use leather in this structure, will it be like this?
It will be flat like this.
The reason is that when we create the sewing line between the line section and the line section,
this sewing line has a default angle of 180 degrees.
That is, it defaults that these two pieces of leather are the same piece of leather.
Then you imagine that if you put one, for example, you take a blanket and wrap it around your foot like this,
will it come over very smoothly?
It won't have those folds.
Then if we want to make the effect of folding,
we might just do it like this.
You will have to adjust the sewing line.
Here I am still changing its size.
Because it is not very good for the angle.
Then here I will put it,
I just put the sewing line type here,
I changed its folding angle to 90 degrees.
When I set a folding angle,
the sewing line between the sheet and the sheet,
naturally forms a corner.
Here I set 90 degrees.
That is to say, this surface and this surface,
the corner in the middle is 90 degrees.
How does this 90 degree set?
It is necessary that this sheet and this sheet
are facing the outside.
Not one is facing the outside,
one is the direction of the hair line.
Anyway, the direction of the two hair lines should be in the right place.
Then after setting the folding angle,
you can see it has a very sharp radial here.
Then after setting the folding angle, you can see it has a very sharp radial here.
Of course, you can also adjust the vertical angle according to your needs, but in general, it is 90 degrees, because in general, its vertical angle is straight.
And then on the shoes side, everyone has a trick, that is, you can adjust the height of the ground in the simulation attribute to the negative value.
Because now our ground is bumpy, just like if you put a piece of fabric in MD and simulate it directly in 3D space, it will not fall off when it falls to the ground.
But when everyone is making shoes, because of shoes, it is inevitable that there will be some bumps on the ground.
Whether you do this foot bottom or do the root that I will make with the fabric later, it will have bumps.
It is recommended to set the property of this ground to negative to avoid some bumps.
And then here I changed the width of this curve.
In general, you just pull this board horizontally like this, and you can give it some volume, so that it will have some bumps on the knee.
And then the root.
The root is like this, that is, I usually use MD, I will try some different methods.
Like here, I just use the fabric to simulate a high-heeled shoe.
Okay.
Of course, in the process of everyone doing it, your root is definitely not so thick.
You can change it in other ways.
Whether it is to import a virtual model from the outside, or you can use the board to fit it.
And then, when I adjust its size, I will constantly compare its effect in 2D and 3D windows.
Like here, you can see that there is a characteristic here.
Is it that the back here is higher, and the front here is lower?
In the case of 3D windows, there must be a point where it is higher.
Now it is so popular.
I usually wear less high-heeled shoes.
It turns out that the roots are so thick now.
And then compare its position again.
Okay, just sew it together.
And then if it is not very convenient to sew in the 2D window, you can sew it directly in the 3D window.
It is also more convenient.
You can see that the roots come out.
But now this root is a little crooked.
You can imagine why it is crooked.
Is it because the line here is shorter?
If the line here is a little longer, is it because it is a flat root?
So you can pull the top a little higher.
Because the whole of it is falling backwards.
It's not going forward.
It's probably because this line is long.
So I tried it.
I was thinking.
At the beginning, I didn't react to this root.
Where did the problem come from?
I still simulated it.
I felt that there seemed to be some problems with this root.
And then I actually tested it in the middle.
Why is there a problem with this root?
In the end, the conclusion I tested was that the back is short.
So don't look at me as if I'm saying it very easily.
Actually, I tried it secretly.
It's just that I didn't put it in.
Then I stretched the length here.
After that, the length of the root matches the length of the root.
This root is straight.
It's smooth.
Isn't it amazing?
You can use fabric to make the root of this high root root.
And then if you have this kind of angle,
don't forget that it has its own angle.
And then it's the same.
Just touch it.
This one.
Same as the sex angle.
In this case,
I even took the entire piece of cloth.
Including the knife and the Own face tag.
I was using this fabric to make the cloth.
It's just too lazy.
But the effect that I can make in AMD
is basically...
Uh...
I don't want to use any other software to do this.
Then I will expand the version file first, and then use the fold-and-arrange tool to fold down the top.
And simulate it.
When I fold down here, these two lines are more sharp.
In the end, I will delete this inner line.
And then just copy and paste it.
Let's take a look at the back.
Next we should be making the gloves.
The gloves are actually similar to making shoes.
And here I will quickly talk about it.
The gloves and shoes are really similar in the way they are made.
Because I am making a relatively tight glove.
If you want to know how to make it thicker,
this kind of...
such as gloves and shoes,
you can look forward to the next live broadcast.
The next live broadcast should be made by Jimmy.
He will have some other ways.
The gloves here are also the same as making shoes.
When making clothes that are relatively tight,
Why didn't I use the virtual model line tool here?
It's because the hands and feet here,
it will pass through a lot of these concave areas.
For example, like the mouth.
The mouth here is a very obvious concave area.
And the underarm.
It will let the 3D line be interrupted.
In such an area,
if you directly draw the virtual model line,
and then go to the sketching board,
you will sketch a very strange line.
Because it goes through a fold.
It's like you've cut a person's skin.
The UV and the 3D window look different.
So I usually prefer to draw a transparent version directly on it.
After that, it's still the same.
In order to prevent the gap between the grid,
I will reduce its strength.
As for the gloves,
because sometimes,
on the wrist,
there might be some foldable wrinkles.
For wrinkles like this,
I will also...
I will...
Because on the arm,
on the small arm here,
there is a piece of muscle that protrudes out.
This part is very easy to fix.
It's tight and eye-catching.
On the wrist,
there will be some foldable wrinkles.
And then,
after that,
I found out that
when people are making gloves,
they might make some...
It's just...
It's not easy to see the foldable wrinkles.
But when making,
for example,
characters like soldiers,
their gloves will have a feeling of standing up.
Let's see where that section is.
OK, here it is.
When making gloves,
we will intentionally make the gloves very large.
For example,
here I made the gloves very large.
You can make them bigger.
Then I will apply some pressure to it.
When applying pressure,
the board itself will rise and fall.
When giving it this kind of pressure,
it won't...
Generally speaking,
if you simulate a cloth,
its own force will cause the cloth
to stick to the person's arm and then go down.
It won't be able to stand up.
Especially on the upper side,
it won't be able to stand up.
But if you apply pressure to it,
it will stand up on its own.
It won't fall down again.
So if you usually want to do something
that can...
counter-physical
some effects,
you can try to increase the pressure.
Sometimes, it will shrink.
Because sometimes the gloves can't come out.
Or if the cloth is too arched,
it will shrink.
I was startled.
I was startled all of a sudden.
You haven't spoken for too long.
No.
Because I was thinking about what to do next.
Suddenly, it scared me a lot.
I don't know why, but sometimes when I sit down, I don't know why, but the curve of my outfit becomes very smooth, and then the wrinkles disappear.
Then I might just manually adjust it a little bit, and then let it have some wrinkles, or else the shoes will be too flat.
Like what I just drew, the front part, because it's too tight, the leather fabric is different from other fabrics.
Once the leather fabric is tight, it looks like it's not folded at all, it's flat.
Then we might just manually adjust its size, and let it have some wrinkles.
On this side, I used fabric to make a simple leather clip.
Then I also drew a...
What should this be called?
A arch.
Anyway, I drew this kind of fabric.
And then after I drew the fabric, I also changed the leather fabric.
And then here, I just wanted to show you guys the buttons and the buttonholes.
For example, on a basic fabric, I added two buttons.
And then I added another fabric.
It's the same.
It's arranged in a similar position.
And then once it's done, I'll use the buttonholes to connect these two pieces together.
After connecting them together, they'll look like buttons.
And then I'll make the buttonhole number smaller.
And then, because the buttonholes in MD can be customized to the buttonhole shape,
which means that this shape doesn't necessarily have to be round.
You can make it a square or a hat.
It's all fine.
And then you use the buttonholes to connect them together.
And then you can quickly position them.
It's like...
For example, if you want to make something that's not as hard as a armor.
For example, something like a leather armor.
Something like this kind of connection.
Because I looked at the reference pictures on the Internet.
The leather armor in the reference picture is also connected like a hat.
Then you can just use the buttonholes to make a replacement.
This is where I'm placing these panels.
Place them up.
And then I'll draw the mask.
Actually, it's not that difficult to draw the mask.
The previous operations were the same.
I also drew along the model's curve.
But there were some problems with the mask.
Because people's heads are very round.
And then our feet and hands are actually relatively flat.
When the mask's head is more three-dimensional,
if you only reserve a little space,
it will be very exciting when you sew it up.
At that time, I didn't feel that there was any problem.
I think it's about the same.
Then I started to simulate.
Forget it, forget it.
Hurry up and stop the simulation and go back.
And then adjust its overall length.
After the simulation is done,
I'll take off this panel when I start the simulation.
And then I'll fix it here with a fake mask.
In fact, panels like this one,
are relatively close to each other.
You may use some shrinkage to make it tighter.
But the mask is very difficult.
Even if you change its friction technique,
it is very difficult to hang on the human body.
Because it's too tight.
It will unconsciously fall down to your neck.
If you encounter such a situation,
just add a few fake wedding rings.
Then the next step is to change the model's movements.
In this case,
because of this kind of belt panel,
this kind of hardware,
its physical properties are particularly hard.
When you change the movement,
this kind of hard object will drag your belt away.
Drag the material that collides with it.
Let them stay still.
If you change the movement,
these belts won't move.
But if you move your body,
there will be some pull.
So at the beginning,
I may reactivate these panels.
After the movement is stable,
I will add them back.
And then,
if you want to change the movement,
whether you use the Morph Target between OBJ,
or you use our Hana,
you can use the default pose.
This pose is actually my own.
It is the most convenient to have a Morph Target.
And then after changing the movement,
because in Marvelous Designer,
once the movement is used,
when the movement is completed,
it will stop the simulation.
But in fact,
your material is not stabilized.
So before you make any changes,
you can start the simulation again.
Let these materials
stabilize each other,
and then do other operations.
And then,
I will re-locate this video.
No, it's too fast.
It won't be up to 4 hours today.
Let's adjust this panel.
After adjusting,
because it is a screen,
if you wear it directly like this,
you will not be able to wear it.
We may use the selection grid tool.
Then select the grid in the middle,
and select it separately.
Then use the positioning tool
to pull it out,
and then turn on the simulation.
This belt will be worn by itself.
When choosing the grid tool,
it is often used
to deal with some insertion problems.
Then draw this handrail.
Adjust the cloth here,
and you can wear it quickly.
And then it's easy to do this with curly hair.
Because Hana's hair
does not have a protective shell,
a spray shell.
How to do the waist belt?
In the last episode,
Jimmy's episode,
when doing the military uniform,
there should be a belt.
Let's take a look.
In order to prevent
conflict with hair,
the most convenient one is
to add a protective shell to the outside of the hair.
A transparent protective shell.
And then you have to reduce
the diameter of the panel.
And then the hat here.
Because in general,
like this kind of hat,
there will be a buckle here,
or it can't be tied up.
So before you draw
the overall big cape,
it's best to buckle it up first.
And then fix it with a fixing pin.
And then the hardening panel here
is because the original panel
is relatively soft.
It pulls each other.
It's a bit unstable.
If it's hardening,
the panel will be a bit flat.
As for the scarf,
you can take a look at the previous episode,
the episode about the little rich woman Hana.
It's about how to tie the scarf.
There should also be a video
about the details of the outfit.
The fastener in the calculation
is to press W and click.
Just click the panel.
You can add the fastener.
And then just manually draw
some covers of the panel.
In order to make it more fast,
like this kind of bigger panel,
I may just open the GPU simulation directly.
And then GPU simulation
will have this kind of sticky problem.
When it's simulated,
adjust its position.
It can be solved in animation.
If you want to remove the cover,
you can only stop at that pin
and then cut the button
and then continue to record.
That's the only way to do it.
There is no K pin.
We also applied for this
for development needs,
but we are not sure
which version will open.
This is the function of K pin.
If you open the GPU simulation,
you can see that
this simulation speed is very fast.
And then if you are using,
uh, usually using MD,
when you jump in the upper left corner,
it's not supported.
Uh, maybe it's just
sometimes you have to update that.
Update the GPU drive.
Can the GPU insertion problem be solved?
We've been trying to find a way to solve this.
But, uh, this development is a bit difficult.
So we can't guarantee that
the next big version
will definitely come out with this function.
Okay, here I just want to do this.
This roll, this pimple.
A method of rolling.
Oh, so, uh, GPU.
Uh, if it's easy to insertion,
I usually suggest that
you can deal with it first
during the simulation process.
Because it's actually easy to insertion,
but it's usually a little better
after you've dealt with it.
The dual precision function of the GPU.
Uh, if you use,
that is, you use the dual precision function,
and then you still use the GPU,
it's actually still a little bit,
uh, not accurate.
Uh, here,
I just gave it a hole,
a hole,
and added a whole piece of fixing pin.
Uh, when you only add
a single fixing pin,
this fixing pin can't rotate.
But when you add a whole piece of fixing pin,
this whole piece of fixing pin
can rotate.
So for the rotation of this whole piece of fixing pin,
you can use it to do some
special effects.
For example, when you roll it up,
you can roll up a part of the material.
What I'm doing here is
to make it a little bit like,
uh,
using the fixing pin
as a protective
measure.
Usually, they'll just
roll up the fixing pin,
and then I'll use the fixing pin
to roll it up in the 3D window first,
and then slowly adjust the fixing pin
to the position of the finger,
the joint of the finger.
And then because the material
might slide during the process,
so I'll add some fixing pins
to it first.
If you're doing a lot of
clothing calculations,
you just start from the innermost layer,
layer by layer.
For Hanfu,
you can watch the Hanfu live stream.
Actually, I feel like
everyone has been asking more about Hanfu lately.
And then, uh,
our neighbor,
our sister company,
Clo,
they're going to be doing some Hanfu live streams recently.
You can look forward to it.
They're definitely more professional
than we are,
in terms of clothing,
and it'll also involve layer processing.
Because the biggest problem with Hanfu
is layer processing.
After using the GPU simulation,
in the end,
I'll use a sewing needle
to fix these two panels
to the position of the virtual model,
to fix it to that point.
And then,
like the button here,
if you've ever recorded an animation,
you'll have a feeling that
the button is very difficult to fix
during the process of recording an animation.
So sometimes,
I might just stop doing the button.
I'll delete this button,
and then draw two inner lines.
I'll use the inner line
to sew the button instead of the button.
After sewing it up,
you can add another fake button
on the outside.
And then,
if you add this button on the outside,
you can turn it off.
That way,
it won't have any problems anymore.
And then,
after using the GPU simulation,
there's one more thing.
You must remember to
switch to the CPU simulation,
and then do the simulation again
before the output.
This way,
the overall simulation effect
will be more stable.
And then,
you're done with one piece of clothing.
I'll look for my project file.
I'll show you.
In the project file,
almost everything
is completed in MD.
Okay.
So, actually,
in MD,
there's a lot of...
Yang Da should still be here.
He's just not talking.
Yeah,
I'm not talking.
Finally,
I'm done with my eye surgery.
Yes,
today's live stream
is a bit long.
Yeah.
The last piece of clothing,
is like this.
And then,
this kind of knife,
because I,
myself,
don't use
other 3D software
very well.
So,
I might use
the thickness
of the knife
in MD
to make it.
Like this.
And then,
the fabric
outside,
I use the fabric
in MD
to wear it.
These ties.
And then,
at the beginning,
when I posted
this,
this rendering,
the final rendering,
they told me,
they said,
this knife
wouldn't be placed
in this position.
It would poke my leg.
And then,
I said,
when I drew it,
I actually felt it.
When I placed this knife,
I already felt it.
But,
that's it.
Yeah,
this knife
was drawn
directly in MD.
I can't say
it's made of hard surface.
You can,
it's actually
still used
fabric
to add
the thickness
and
the edge
to make it
a little bit
simpler.
Before,
I posted
a package
in the group.
You can also
do it in MD.
Let me find
the file
where it is.
There will be
a live broadcast.
Don't worry about this.
Why is it
so...
What is this?
It...
I'm using
Fujifilm.
Of course,
it's on the surface.
If you want to open it,
you can make
this version
thinner.
Let me find it.
Although the thickness
is not reflected,
it's because
you opened it
on this
texture surface.
It shows
that it's
thin.
No matter how you
change the thickness,
it's
not thick.
It's thin.
It's mainly used
to identify
the front and
back sides
of a fabric.
Its front side
is colored
and the back side
is a little black.
The thick texture
on the surface
is thick.
Do you have any
questions
during the
MD process?
Let me find
the package
I made
before.
Shouzi,
Shouzi.
Shouzi
is
you have
to
make
it
look
like
this.
Shouzi
is
made into
a
long
fabric.
It's
made into
a
long
one.
You have to
use
a short
length
to make
a long
fabric.
It's
made
into
a
long
fabric.
So
you can
make
a
long
fabric
with
a
short
fabric.
So
it's
not
the effect of the red color will be more obvious.
Basically, it's all about the thickness of the text.
Because the UV will...
Because in AMD itself, if you export with the thickness,
the UV will have problems.
I found this file.
Oh, this is a package I made with AMD before.
The script, this is...
The script, you can take a look at our handbook.
Because the current script is still a relatively basic script.
It's not able to make a very complete set of animations.
Like this package, you can see...
Why can you guys be so funny?
Why is it so hard?
Because I didn't do the simulation.
If I do the simulation, there will be problems.
Look, imagine the structure of this package.
This is something I did a long time ago.
Like this one, is it a circle?
A stick.
Then in AMD...
Then in AMD, it's a circle.
Then you increase its rendering thickness to 75.
It becomes a round stick like this.
And then here,
I drew a flat shape.
This is also a sketch of the brain.
And then,
use the edge curve to control the angle here.
I don't...
Yeah, you have to simulate.
So I'm going to take this whole thing,
a whole piece,
and then export the file.
Export as OBJ.
Yes, you can.
You can export a single completed project like this with the thickness.
Because anyway, I'm just going to export the whole thing with the thickness.
I don't care about its depth.
Because it's not very...
It's not the kind of fabric or clothing.
And then if you sit here,
you have to imagine that this part of real life is thin.
Then its rendering thickness may not be very large.
You see, I'm usually studying these things.
How to use fabric in AMD to do this kind of thing.
Yeah.
Make a model with a thickness of a parameter.
Then if it's like this,
if it's side design,
it's than itself,
but then its rendering thickness is different.
Its crease area is also different.
I told you previously about Han
I've tried round balls before, but the project file for round balls is very weird, I can't find it.
You have to use two round balls, and then increase the pressure to 50, and then decrease the bending force a little bit,
and then the bending force of the goldfish sand should be reduced to about 1 or 2.
Then it will blow like a balloon, and it will blow into a round ball.
But to be honest, the most convenient way to make a round ball is to pull a round ball directly into it.
Although you can't use two round balls, the most convenient way is to pull a round ball directly into it.
Yeah, I actually don't understand. Isn't it very fast to pull a round ball directly into it?
It's not easy to calculate the length of the shaft.
If you want to pull a round ball directly into it, you still have to do it layer by layer.
If you want to do it layer by layer, you can use a shrink to make it close to the model first, and then put the outer layer on top of it.
Also, when you make a round ball, don't use arranging points.
A round ball is a very large piece of flat surface, and arranging points are not very useful.
Do you have any more questions?
Or if you have any questions you want to ask Yang Da, you can ask him now.
Oh, why do you need to hide the edit button tool?
You can unzip it.
Wait a minute, it's in the user ID here.
Then the user interface, there is a working group, you can open it.
You can use the unzip button tool to cut it into two pieces.
You can, for example, let's assume that there is a cut line in the middle.
Select it, use the edit button to select it, and then force it to 0, then it will be very obvious.
The curve is not made layer by layer.
It's just that you solve it layer by layer, and then simulate the whole thing together.
And then the whole thing is leaded together.
You can take a look at the reference video like this.
Use other software to complete the model, lead to mp calculation.
If you are talking about clothes, first of all, you can think about it.
The model you can make in other software, is its UV itself correct?
If its UV is better to extract the version,
That is to say,
First of all, it does not overlap, and secondly, it does not have a blank space.
And then it is more normal to connect, that is, there is no particular weird version, that is no problem.
If you don't need to extract, that is, you don't need to extract the version from the UV,
That is, there will be a certain degree of loss.
You may need to use the formulating tool like this.
How do you deal with the line interface before you import the gd sculpt?
This...
We talked about this problem earlier.
Yes, yes, Mr. Yang talked about this problem earlier.
And then you can wait for our next broadcast.
Broadcast upload, like this.
Wow, this live broadcast today is a lot of work.
It's a little longer than I thought, but it doesn't feel too long.
It's mainly because Mr. Yang talked about it, and I heard that it was really interesting.
I think it's really useful to talk about the gd sculpt.
Because I've been wanting to learn drawing recently.
And then I think it's very good for gd sculpting.
It's better than the one I've been doing 3D for so many years.
Still...
I need to be more precise.
After listening to it, I think, oh, it's because of this.
These are some of the methods.
Actually, there are a lot of things that we haven't talked about yet.
It's still not very clear.
In the previous video, there was a part about re-taping.
Today there is.
Anyway, today there must be.
There is a talk about taping.
I've been listening to it since lunch.
All by myself.
So, if you want to open a Marvelous Designer class at school,
or if you want to cooperate with our software,
for example, if you want to use the official software,
in fact, students can contact us.
We will consider whether or not you want to open such classes at your school,
or if you want to cooperate with the school.
A tablet can be divided into two.
Who asked this?
Can a tablet be divided into two?
You can draw an internal line,
and then right-click to cut it,
and it will be divided into two.
Then, everyone, bye-bye.
See you next time.
See you in the next live broadcast.
Okay, okay, we will upload it a little earlier.
Next time, everyone will also watch the live broadcast.
Bye-bye.
I don't have to pay.
Everyone can pay attention to Yang Da's Art Station.
I also think Yang Da's work is very good.
Bye-bye, all of you too.
Bye-bye.
You, too.
Bye-bye, everyone.
Bye-bye.
We will upload live broadcast soon.
Bye-bye, everyone.
Eat breakfast early.
Rest early.
Bye-bye.
itan o
Okay.
Bye-bye.